-- ==本影片由 CMCT 团队 荣誉出品==--
更多精彩影视 请访问 http://www.cmct.cc
影片压制：死亡骑士　字幕翻译：咖啡 小动物 灰灰 Shakuras
翻译校对：Shakuras　字幕调校：死亡骑士　招募Q号：76846146
Oh,Father,turn it up.
哦 爸爸 声音再大些
Please,Mr. Dragomir,I love this song.
拜托了 德拉戈米尔先生 我喜欢这歌
This song is sick...
这歌听着让人作呕
the traditional "vomit" definition of the word.
用传统的"呕吐"一词形容真是再合适不过了
Shut up,Andre. Me and Rose want to hear it.
闭嘴 安德烈 我和萝丝都很喜欢这歌
"Rose and I," Lissa,"Rose and I."
"萝丝和我" 莉莎 是"萝丝和我"
I think the tune is rather catchy.
我想这曲调相当让人着迷啊
Lissa?
莉莎
Lissa. Hey,Lissa,wake up.
莉莎 嘿 莉莎 醒醒
- You're having a bad dream. - It wasn't a dream.
- 你做了一个噩梦 - 那不是梦
I know. The accident.
我知道 那是意外
Sorry. Not again.
抱歉 不会再发生了
You know,ever since that night,I still can't get used to it.
你知道 自从那晚发生之后 我始终无法适应
You being in my head,it's so weird.
你能进入我脑中 这感觉非常怪异
You should know by now,with us,
你现在应该知道我们的生活
"weird" doesn't begin to cover it.
已经不能用"怪异"来形容了
Why can't you be like a normal teenage girl
你为什么不能像一个正常的女孩那样
and dream about hot,naked guys on unicorns?
梦见骑着独角兽的火辣男生呢？
Does it have to be unicorns?
为什么非要是独角兽？
Of course not. It could be Jet Skis,mechanical bulls or...
当然不一定 也可以是水上摩托车 机械公牛或是
Why do you have a scary poster of an American ex-president?
你为什么有一张美国前总统的可怕的海报
Well,you told me I needed to blend more into Oregano society.
好吧 你不是告诉过我 要多融入到俄勒冈社会的吗
We're in Oregon. You know you're completely hopeless
我们就在俄勒冈啊 我觉得你已经彻底无望了
as a human being,right?
作为一个人类来说 是吗
I'm still adjusting,Rose.
我一直都在调整适应 萝丝
It's been less than a year since we ran away from the academy,
我们离开那座学院差不多快一年的时间了
two years since the crash.
距离那次车祸也已经有两年的时间了
Don't you ever stop to think about everything that we've gone through?
你就没有曾经停下来思考一下 我们已经经历的事情吗
Stopping is for losers. I only think about keeping us moving
对于弱者来说才需要停下来 我所考虑的只有不断地向前
and keeping you safe.
同时保证你的安全
Does anyone even remember us?
还有人记得我们吗
You really think the academy's still trying to hunt us down?
你真的认为那座学院仍然在追捕我们吗
Absolutely. I think we may have to get plastic surgery.
当然确定 我想我们可能有必要做整形手术
No,don't,please.
不 不会的 拜托
- Yes? No? - No.
- 要还是不要 - 不要
- Just like this? You like it? - Rose,no.
- 就像这样 你喜欢吗 - 萝丝 我可不喜欢
- Whoa. When was the last time you...? - I'm not hungry.
- 喔 你最近是什么时候 - 我不饿的
Is exactly what you say every time you're hungry.
每次说这些的时候 正是你饿了的时候
Come to the kitchen. I'll make your favorite.
到厨房来 我会弄些你的最爱的
Are you... are you sure about this?
你确定 你确定要这样吗
Bon appétit.
希望你喜欢
- Thanks. - What are friends for?
- 谢谢 - 朋友就该这样嘛
You jealous,Oscar?
你嫉妒么 奥斯卡？
What are you looking at?
你在看什么？
Do I still have anything on my...?
我还有什么东西在我的
Lissa,smile. They're watching. Not a drill.
莉莎 保持微笑 他们正在观察 这不是演习
- What's out there? Not Strigoi? - No,not Strigoi,thank God. Guardians.
- 那边有什么 不是血族吧 - 不是血族 感谢上帝 是守护者
Keep close,just like we practiced.
跟紧 就像练习一样
Lissa,go.
莉莎 快跑
- Did you have to hurt them? - Did I have to hurt them?
- 一定要伤害他们吗？- 我有必要伤害他们吗？
You're welcome. Get out the map,Gandhi.
别在意了 拿地图出来吧 甘地
We'll head north into Canada.
我们要向北进入加拿大
Did you really bring that fur ball?
你真的要带着那只毛球吗？
I couldn't just abandon him.
我不会扔下它他的
Hells,yes.
该死 好吧
Rose.
萝丝
Princess Vasilisa Dragomir.
瓦西里萨·德拉戈米尔公主
My name is Dimitri Belikov.
我的名字是迪米特里·别利科夫
I've come to take you back to St. Vladimir's Academy.
我是来带你回到圣弗拉基米尔学院的
Listen,comrade,to get to her,you're gonna have to go through me.
听着 朋友 想要带走她必须先过我这关
Like I said,"weird" doesn't begin to cover it.
就像我说的那样 已经不能用 "怪异" 来形容了
My best friend Lissa Dragomir is a royal member
我最好的朋友莉莎·德拉戈米尔是一名有魔力的王室成员
of a magical,ancient race: the Moroi.
属于古老的种族：莫里族
The Moroi don't wear black capes,turn into bats or sleep in.
莫里族不需要带黑色的斗篷 不用变成蝙蝠或睡在棺椁里
Daylight annoys yet doesn't kill them,and they don't sparkle,either.
日光会给他们带来困扰却不会杀死他们 他们也不会身上起火
But,yes,like most creatures with fangs,the Moroi live off blood.
但是 和大部分有尖牙的生物一样 莫里族需要以吸血为生
But they don't live forever,that's why they need us.
他们不会永久生存 这就是他们需要我们的原因
My name is Rose Hathaway
我的名字是萝丝·海瑟薇
and like these other guys,I'm a Dhampir.
和这些家伙一样 是拜尔族的
We're the protectors,the guardians.
我们是保护者 守护者
Only half Moroi,
因为只有一半莫里族血统
I can eat a bacon cheeseburger or whatever else I want.
我可以吃培根芝士汉堡或者任何想吃的东西
Dhampir lives are dedicated to protecting the Moroi.
拜尔族生存的目的 就是为了保护莫里族
We live by one simple expression: they come first.
我们的信仰非常简单 一切以莫里族为先
Only nothing's ever simple.
没有比这更简单的了
Handcuffs? There's got to be a compliment in there somewhere.
手铐 终于有值得称赞的地方了
So you're taking us back to the academy.
你打算把我们带回学院
Tell me,how bad is it gonna be?
告诉我 会有多糟糕呢？
Nothing?
没什么吗？
You know,I kept the princess safe and hidden
你知道 我要确保公主的安全和隐蔽
for an entire year before you got lucky.
为了在你到来前的这一整年里
- Congratulations. - It speaks.
- 祝贺你 - 说的不错
Wow,that's a lot of molnija marks you got there.
喔 有许多的莫尔里加印在你那里
You've killed six Strigoi?
你已经杀了6名血族吸血鬼了吗
We were afraid that we'd run into one of them back there.
我们担心会遇上返回那里的他们中的一员
If you had run into a Strigoi,
如果你遇上一名血族吸血鬼的话
we wouldn't be having this conversation.
我们就不会有这样一场谈话了
This is your idea of a conversation?
这就是你对谈话的想法吗
Exactly.
没错
We are here. Open the gate.
我们到了 把门打开
Anyone there?
有人吗？
Where is everyone?
大家都去哪了？
- Let's go! - Lissa!
- 快跑 - 莉莎
Move,move!
快跑 快跑
Stay in the car.
待在车里
No!
不
I've got this one. Stay here.
我追这个 待在这里
What's going on out there?
外面发生了什么
Stay here.
待在里面
Spiridon.
斯皮里敦
Welcome back,Dimitri.
欢迎回来 迪米特里
And then there's group number three: the bad vampires,the Strigoi.
那就是第三族吸血鬼：邪恶的吸血鬼 血族
Evil bloodsuckers that only come out at night
他们是只在夜晚出现的邪恶吸血鬼
and can only be killed by a silver stake.
而且只有银锥才能杀死他们
It takes five of our best to kill one of their worst.
要牺牲我们中最好的5个 才能杀死他们中最差的1个
If you're lucky,they'll just rip you apart,
如果你有幸被选中的话 他们会把你撕成碎片
but they can also turn you into one of them.
但是他们也会把你变成他们中的一员
Strigoi were the true monsters of our nightmares.
血族吸血鬼是我们噩梦中的真正的怪物
For all the stories,the warnings,and the training films,
对于所有的故事 所有的警告以及训练影像中
I had never seen one up close.
我还从来没有近距离看到过他们
I told you to stay in the car.
我告诉过你要待在车里
We're clear.
已经安全了
And there it was. Goodbye,Facebook.
还是到这儿了 再见 脸书
Goodbye,iPhone 5.
再见 苹果5手机
Hello,St. Vladimir's.
你好 圣弗拉米尔
It is not just another school.
这不仅是另一所学校
It's another universe.
这是另一个世界
Moroi and Dhampir students come from all over the world
莫里族和拜尔族的学生来自于世界各地
to study history,science,math,and all the other boring stuff,
学习历史 自然科学 数学以及其他无聊的东西
but around fourth period,
但是需要在第四阶段开展
we Dhampir go off and learn fun new ways to maim and kill,
我们拜尔族会去学习新的搏斗方式
while,for the Moroi,it's magic time.
同时 对于莫里族来说就是学习魔法的时间
Water,earth,fire,air.
包括水 土 火 风
You see,it's not just their diet
你知道的 并不仅仅是因为莫里族的饮食习惯
that makes the Moroi special,
才使他们变得特别
and some are more special than others.
使他们中的一些吸血鬼与其他吸血鬼相比更加特别
Our secret society has its own government
我们的隐秘的社会中有着自己的管理体系
that alternates leaders from 12 royal families.
就是领导者需要从12个皇室家族中选出
That's Queen Tatiana up top,but my girl Lissa is in the mix.
塔提安娜皇后处在最高层 我的朋友莉莎也在其中
You can see why the princess leaving the academy was such a scandal,
你现在明白 为什么公主离开学院会被认为是一个奇耻大辱
and me helping her was worse.
以及我帮助她会使情况变得更糟的原因了
Damn,back to Vampire Academy.
该死 回到吸血鬼学院
Please don't say Vampire Academy. You know how I feel about the "V" word.
请别说出吸血鬼学院的名字 你知道我对字母"V"的感觉的
Sorry.
真抱歉
It's not like the drinking of blood is your main source of sustenance.
这可不像以吸血为主要生存来源的你啊
No,wait,that's exactly what it is.
不 等等 事实就是这样的
They just had to bring us back in the middle of the night.
他们还是必须在半夜将我们带回去的
So not cool... 1:00 a.m.,end of fifth period.
所以不会太冷 凌晨1点钟 第五阶段的结束
Ew,it looks like Aaron's tried to replace you
哦 看上去像是阿伦试图要用一个
with a little keychain version.
小鸟依人的妹子来代替你
God,I hate high school.
上帝啊 我讨厌高中
Princess. Headmistress Kirova is ready for you.
公主 基洛娃校长已经在等你了
Come on.
来吧
It's all so unprecedented. I'm at a loss coming up with proper punishment.
这真是前所未有啊 我会从损失中提出适当的惩罚措施的
As Lissa's guardian...
作为莉莎的守护者
You're not an official guardian,Hathaway.
你并不是正规的守护者 海瑟薇
You are a novice.
你只是一名新手
You put Vasilisa at the mercy of the Strigoi,
你将瓦西里萨置于血族吸血鬼的控制之中
who would love to destroy,or even worse,transform...
他们喜欢破坏甚至会作出更恶劣的行为 改造等
It was my idea to leave. Rose only did what...
我的观点是离开 萝丝只有按照
A trained guardian knows...
一个受过专业训练的守护者知道
Ellen,please.
艾伦 请进
- Victor. - Lissa.
- 维克多 - 莉莎
Ah.
啊
Prince Dashkov,you look so...
达什科夫王子 你看上去
Yes. My Sandovsky's syndrome has gotten worse.
是的 我的珊多夫斯基综合征变得更糟糕了
Oh,Victor,we never meant to worry you.
哦 维克多 我们没打算讨扰你
Headmistress,
校长
these girls have been through so much.
这些女孩已经经历了如此之多
As provost of this school
作为这所学校的教务长
and Lissa's father's oldest friend,
及莉莎父亲的老朋友
I beg you,look into your heart.
我请求你 扪心自问
Vasilisa,I have the utmost sympathy
瓦西里萨 我给予你最大的同情
for the loss of your parents and your brother,Andre.
对于你失去父母和兄弟一事 安德烈
But why did you flee a heavily guarded compound
但是你为什么要逃离
of Moroi students from all over the world?
由来自世界各地的莫里族吸血鬼组成的严密戒备呢
It's not easy to explain.
这不是一两句话可以说清的
Lissa felt more in danger here in your secure environment
莉莎在你构建的防护圈中感觉更危险
than on the outside as an anonymous teenager.
与作为一个匿名青年生活在外面世界相比
Fascinating. This is where you give me specifics.
太棒啦 这就是你给我的解释
Where's Ms. Karp?
卡普女士在哪
She should be here.
她应该在这里
She can maybe shed some light onto the situation.
她对这种情况或许可以给出自己的一些看法
Ms. Karp is no longer part of this institution.
卡普女士已经不是这个机构的一员了
I...
我
This is where you give me specifics. What do you mean?
这就是你给我的解释 你什么意思
It's not important!
这不重要
Vasilisa Dragomir is from one of the 12 royal families.
瓦西里萨·德拉戈米尔 是来自于12个皇室家族的一员
She's the last of the Dragomir line.
她是德拉戈米尔家族最后一脉
With my condition taking the Dashkov family out of contention,
如果不考虑我们家族的话确实是这样
Lissa is a possible successor to the throne.
莉莎是王位的可能继承者
But you,Hathaway,a Dhampir girl cut off from the community,
但是你 海瑟薇 是已从这个团体中排除的女孩
out on civilian streets without a dime or a Social Security number?
你竟然在人类社会大摇大摆
"Blood whore" is such an ugly term,
"出卖血液"是一个如此丑陋的词语
but I'm sure Moroi men on business trips would pay a lot
但是我敢肯定莫里族人出差时 会支付更多
for the especially sweet taste.
为了获得特别的甜点
Headmistress Kirova.
基洛娃校长
- They have the bond. - That's... that's impossible.
- 他们有联结 - 那 那是不可能的
In my brief observation period,
以我短暂的观察来看
Rose could tell what Lissa was thinking or feeling,
萝丝能够清楚莉莎的想法或感觉
sometimes without being in the same place.
有时不在同一个地方
What a rare and wonderful gift.
多么难得和美妙的天赋啊
This doesn't take away from the fact that Rose Hathaway is wild,dangerous...
这并不会否定萝丝的野蛮 危险等事实
- insubordinate,vulgar. - Right here,folks. Right here.
- 不顺从的 卑微 - 这里 大家 在这里
But the number of female Dhampir guardians has gone down
但是女性拜尔族守护者 已经快速地走下坡路了
way too much to risk losing one with such potential.
致使没有人愿意 冒着失去被保护人的风险选择她们
Ellen,what this impressive new guardian says seems reasonable.
艾伦 这些出众的新守护者的话似乎有些道理
We're so sorry,Headmistress.
我们非常抱歉 校长
After the crash,I lacked a strong parental figure to confide in.
那次变故后 我失去了可以倾诉的强有力的臂膀
I'm afraid Rose and I got in way over our heads.
恐怕萝丝和我也会遇到阻力
Two crazy kids.
两个疯狂的小鬼
Hathaway can stay,but no extracurricular activities,
海瑟薇可以留下 但是没课外活动
no parties,no socializing,nothing resembling fun.
没派对 没社交以及类似的活动
Take the princess to her royal quarters and find a broom closet for...
将公主带到她的皇家住处 并找到一个储物柜用来
Oh,Rose,I almost forgot.
哦 萝丝 我几乎忘记了
A telegram.
一份电报
From Mom.
你妈妈
Kirova flipping out and Lissa using compulsion to save my ass,
把基洛娃找来 同时莉莎的强势保护了我
just another night at St. Vladimir's.
在圣弗拉米尔的另一个晚上
Wow. This place definitely brought back memories.
喔 这地方把我的记忆都拉回来了
Come on,over here.
过来 这边
Before the accident,my father used to say
事故发生前 我爸爸常常说
that for a Moroi not declaring a magic
对于一个莫里族吸血鬼来说没有掌控一种魔法
is like not going through puberty.
就像没有经历青春期是一样的
Yeah,and he also used to say practice during the day
是的 他常常说要在白天中
while the world,your world,is sleeping.
全世界 以及你的世界 都在休息时加以练习
Let's make some magic.
来 施展一些魔法
Perfect.
非常好
Fire and water.
火属性与水属性
That's my Moroi.
你是我需要守护的莫里族
- Rose... - Don't leave me hanging.
- 萝丝 - 别让我一直举着
Rose,you know how I feel about high-fives.
萝丝 你知道我不喜欢击掌
Ladies. It's after 11:00 a.m.,girls. You should be in bed.
女士们 已经过了上午11点了 女孩们 你们应该上床休息了
The sun has cleared the trees,and it won't be kind,Your Highness.
太阳毫不留情的映照在树上 殿下
I never got a chance to express my condolences at the funeral.
我从来都没有机会在葬礼上表达我的哀悼
But I am so heartened
但是我是如此的欣慰
by the extraordinary recovery you've both made.
因为看到你们获得了非凡的恢复力
And don't worry,Princess.
不要担心 公主
I never officially declared a magic,either.
我也从来没有正式地学到过一种魔法
And look how I turned out.
看看我最后会如何
Ms. Karp's so different from the other instructors.
卡普女士真是与众不同
It's really refreshing.
令人耳目一新
The thing that I like the most about her is she's not strange or creepy at all
我最感兴趣的是 她没有变得陌生和令人毛骨悚然
- It's hurt. - It's more than hurt. It's done.
- 它受害了 - 它不仅仅受了伤 已经死了
Leave it. Come on,let...
离开它 过来 我们一起
That was unique.
那是独一无二
Lissa.
莉莎
Lissa?
Hey,Liss.
嘿 利斯
- It's good to see you. - Aaron.
- 很高兴见到你 - 阿伦
Guessing your new girlfriend practices water magic. Classy.
我猜你新女朋友在练习水系魔法 真漂亮
Yeah. Hey,I'm sorry.
是的 嘿 抱歉啊
Mia gets jealous,but deep down,she's sweet.
米亚很是嫉妒 只是放在心底而已 她是很好的
Back off,bitch. He's mine now.
放弃吧 该死的 他现在是我的
Very deep down,apparently.
很显然是在内心深处
How does it feel to leave at the top and come back at the bottom?
离开了人生顶点 而在低谷时 那是怎样的感觉呢
Don't like what I'm saying?
不喜欢我说的吗
What are you gonna do about it?
你要做什么
Thanks for asking.
感谢你的提问
I'm gonna go to a quiet place
我要去一个安静的地方
and be very depressed that this is my new life.
虽然很沮丧 但这是我的新生活
All Dhampir novices transfer to the next training station.
所有拜尔族初学者都会转移到下一个培训地点
Everyone transfer to their next training station.
每个人都会转移到他们的下一个培训地点
Dimitri is a God.
迪米特里是上帝
I hear he tracked them down to Oregon,
我听说他跟踪他们到了俄勒冈州
and when Rose tried to put up a fight,he handed her her ass.
当萝丝准备开战的时候 他已经把她撂倒了
And what was left of that ass got chewed up by Headmistress Kirova.
萝丝回到学校后又让基洛娃校长狠狠地数落了一顿
Surely,you have something more interesting to discuss than my ass.
当然 与我的悲惨遭遇相比 你一定有一些更加有趣的话题
- Your boobies? - Quit while you're alive,Mason.
- 你是傻子吗 - 当心点哦 梅森
What up,baby?
怎么了 伙计？
Ooh.
噢
Forgot the secret handshake. That hurts.
忘掉那个秘密的握手吧 不堪回首
You know,I'm gonna make you pay for your booby comment.
你知道 我要让你为自己的犯傻付出代价
Old Rose maybe,but you've missed a year of training.
也许是过去的萝丝 但是你已经错过一年的培训了
Yeah,you needed that year to catch up with what I was born with.
是的 你需要那一年的努力来赶上我的天赋
Prepare to...
准备着
Ow!
哦
Sorry,Rose. Don't hate me.
抱歉 萝丝 别恨我
I'd hate you more if you held back.
你如果回来的话我会恨死你的
They have these things in the outside world...
在外面的世界他们有
Pinkberry and mini taquitos,
粉莓 迷你墨西哥玉米饼
Toaster Strudel...
以及果馅卷等
Oh,no. Not this again.
哦 不 不会又来了吧
Don't worry. I don't bite.
别担心 我不会咬的
Well... only literally.
好的 只是是字面的意思
What are you doing here?
你在这里做什么呢
This is where I come to get away.
这就是我要逃脱的地方
Hey,this was my... special place
嘿 这是我的 特别地点
before it was your special place.
在它成为你的特别地点之前
What do you have to get away from,Princess?
你到底在逃避什么呢 公主？
What do you know about pain? Break a nail off in your tiara?
你知道什么是痛苦吗 难道要赌上你的身份名誉吗
- Excuse me,after a car crash... - You got off easy.
- 抱歉 我认为在那次车祸后 - 你还算是不错的
How dare you! Do you have any idea what it's like to lose your family?
你敢 对于失去家庭的你来说有什么想法吗
Oh. Sorry.
哦 抱歉
You know you're talking to Christian Ozera,right?
你知道你正在和克里斯琴·奥泽拉讲话 对吗
Parents transformed themselves into Strigoi...
父母将他们变成血族吸血鬼
When your folks died,there was a pretty funeral,
当你的家人去世 就会有一场盛大的葬礼
and everybody cried.
并且所有人都会为之哭泣
When my mother and father were hunted down,everybody cheered.
当我的父母都被追杀时 大家都很高兴
I hate what they chose to become...
我讨厌他们选择变成
but they were still my parents.
但是他们终究是我的父母
A Strigoi can't enter holy ground.
血族吸血鬼无法进入圣地
Is that why you come to the church?
这是你到教堂的原因吗
To prove to everyone you haven't turned?
为了向大家证明你没有改变吗
Get away from that freak.
远离那个怪人
Maybe I just like the way the moonlight hits this spot.
可能我仅仅喜欢的是 月光打在这里的方式而已
It's as if you're on another planet.
这就像你生活在其他星球那样
What was it like... outside the academy?
学院外面的世界是怎样的呢
It was kind of scary,just the two of us out there,
有点吓人 只有我们两个人在那里
but... it was also kind of great.
但是也很厉害
No one knew who I was.
没人知道我是谁
It does sound kind of great.
好像很厉害的样子
But what did you do for blood?
但是为了血液你会做什么呢
I mean,it's not like you can pick it up at 7-Eleven.
我的意思是 这可不是你能在7-11便利店可以得到的
Or so I've read.
或者是我读到的
Don't you say anything,girl. People will get the wrong idea.
不要说任何话 宝贝 其他人会误解的
You and Rose,all alone on the road. I have my theories.
你和萝丝 都独自走在路上 我有自己的理论
Promise me you won't tell your friends these theories.
答应我 你不会告诉你的朋友这些理论的
I promise you I have no friends to tell.
我答应你不会告诉别人的
Stop staring at each other all...
别再互相凝视了
- ...gooey like. - Hathaway!
- 像浆糊那样 - 海瑟薇
Look alive!
醒醒
Comrade Belikov.
别里科夫同事
They ran me ragged. What do you say we go easy today?
他们让我精疲力尽 你说我们今天做些什么会顺利些呢
- Perhaps discuss a bit of theory. - Of course,Rose. I understand.
- 或许可以讨论一些理论 - 当然 萝丝 我明白的
How do you say "what a dick" in Russian?
"该死的家伙"用俄语怎么说呢
Did you even go to a gym out there?
你会去那里的体育馆吗
I took a couple of spinning classes.
我参加了一套纺织课程
Do you really think beating me up is gonna help me face a live Strigoi?
你真的认为打倒我的话 会帮我面对一个血族人？
After your performance last night,
看到你昨晚的表现之后
if you see a Strigoi,I recommend running.
如果你看见一个血族吸血鬼的话 我建议还是跑吧
Now,give me ten sets of lines.
现在 给我10套线
You know,this country has a concept called "positive reinforcement."
你知道 这里被称为"积极防御的阵地"
Rose,your bond is special.
萝丝 你的联结很特别
You're an ideal choice to guard Vasilisa when you both graduate.
当你们都毕业时 你是守护瓦西里萨的理想选择
But if you want to be with her,you need to be ready for anything.
如果你想和她在一起的话 你需要做好万全的准备
- Ow! - Wow.
- 哦 - 噢
You look how I feel.
你知道我的感觉
I look how I feel.
我也清楚自己的感觉
How's that "under the radar" plan working out,Highness?
"雷达监控"计划制定的怎样了 海瑟斯
Not so much.
还不行
If you need a shoulder to cry on,
如果需要一个肩膀靠着哭泣的话
use mine,not Christian Ozera's.
我的可以 不要用克里斯琴·奥泽拉的
- Who told you? - I was sort of... you know,there.
- 谁告诉你的 - 我是那种 你知道的
Oh,not again. That's so gross.
不 别再这样了 情况已经如此严重
I know,and it was,like,the longest one yet.
我知道 就像最长的一个那样
- You seriously can't turn it off? - I don't know.
- 你真的不会关掉它吗 - 我不知道
Have you ever seen me go to the bathroom?
你看见过我走进那间浴室吗
No,but thank you for giving me something to look forward to.
没有 不过谢谢你让我有了些许期待
Oh,shut up. Oh!
哦 闭嘴 哦
No wonder I'm so cranky. I'm starving.
难怪我胡思乱想 我快饿死了
And now,for the obligatory cafeteria scene,sort of.
呐 现在到餐厅啦 姑且这么叫吧
Ever wonder what happened to that friend of yours,
曾经想过你的朋友们 因迷恋吸血鬼书籍及表演
obsessed with vampire books and shows?
会发生什么吗
It's called the human feeder program.
这就是所谓的人类供给者计划
Human civilians systematically giving their blood.
人类可以系统地供给他们的血液
I forgot how much I did not miss this.
我忘记自己有多久没有错过这个了
Hey,no feeder is brought here against their will.
嘿 没带来供给者可是违背他们的意愿的
They can leave any time that they want to.
他们可以在任何想离开的时候离去
Yeah,it's just a one-year service limit,
是的 这仅仅是一年服务的限制
and their memories are officially compulsed upon departure.
并且当他们离开的时候记忆会被抹去
That's completely normal.
那是非常正常的
Don't feel too sorry for the feeders.
不要对那些供给者感觉太内疚
If you recall,the bite does get something out of the process.
如果你会想的话就会发现 在咬的过程中会有其他的东西
- Oh,there's Norrine. Here. - Hey! Look at you!
- 哦 那是诺芮恩 来 - 嘿 看看你自己
- How are you? - Yeah,good.
- 最近好吗 - 我很好
Here.
这里
OK.
好的
Rose! Come and keep a decrepit man company.
萝丝 过来帮我照顾一下这个老伙计
Decrepit? You're just saying that so I won't kick your ass in five-card draw.
老伙计？别开玩笑了
Tell me,my darling,while you were gone,
告诉我 亲爱的 当你不在的时候
did Lissa get any closer to declaring?
莉莎对魔法的掌控有任何进步吗
There's not a lot of places to practice magic in Portland.
在波特兰可没有太多的地方能够练习魔法
Oh,true,true.
哦 是真的 是真的
On the subject of non-declarers,
对非行为主体来说
I want to know why,when I brought up Ms.Karp's name yesterday,
我想知道 为什么当我昨日提起卡普女士的名字
you all acted like I put a porcupine in a hot tub.
你的表现就像看到我 把一只豪猪扔到火盆中去一样
Karp has always been a few corpuscles shy of a full artery.
卡普总是对全方位的保护有点害羞
She didn't have a Dhampir to look after her.
她没有拜尔族守护者来照顾她
I know you have your special bond with Lissa,
我知道你和莉莎有特殊的联结
but it makes your escape that much more alarming.
但是它使你规避了更多的警报
I'm on your side,Rose,
我是和你一条战线的 萝丝
but we live in a world where the bogeymen are real.
但是我们生活在一个确实存在恶魔的世界中
I know. I'm still a little freaked-out.
我知道 但还是会有一些小惊吓
I was there last night when that Strigoi attacked,
昨晚血族吸血鬼攻击的时候我在那里
and I just... I totally choked.
我简直 吓尿了
Don't be so down on yourself,Rose.
别灰心 萝丝
Why are you...
为什么你
I know you have your life mission to protect Lissa,
我知道保护莉莎是你生命的目标
but would you now and again look out for my Natalie?
但是你可以偶尔照顾照顾我的娜塔莉吗
Mm...
嗯
She's a goofball,but I do cherish her.
她是个欢乐的小二货 但是我非常珍惜她
Yes. Well,she worships her father.
是的 她崇拜她的父亲
She would do anything for you.
她会为你做任何事
I must go to her.
我必须去她那里
Hey.
嘿
Hi.
嗨
Do I have anything...
难道我有
Just fat-lady feeder breath. Here.
只是有肥胖女人供给者的气味
So,do you even know your feeders?
你了解自己的供给者吗
Norrine's recently divorced,and she's catching up on some me-time.
诺芮恩最近离婚了 正好可以与我的时间相吻合
She writes Twilight fan-fiction.
她在写些关于《暮光之城》的东西
- Have you read any of it? - Oh,God,no.
- 你有阅读吗 - 哦 上帝 还没有
Rose,Princess Vasilisa. I mean,Lissa.
萝丝 瓦西里萨公主 我的意思是 莉莎
You said I could call you Lissa,but if I can't anymore,
你说过我可以称呼你为莉莎 但是如果不能这样称呼的话
- that's totally fine. - Hello,Natalie.
- 那真是太棒了 - 你好 娜塔莉
By the soul of St. Vlad's,so much has happened.
根据圣弗拉米尔的的意思 已经发生了如此多事
Nothing bigger than your escape,of course. Why did you escape?
当然 没什么比你逃跑更大的事情了 为什么要逃跑呢
Did you hear Sheila Flight and Bruce Bugsburger broke up?
听说席拉·福莱特跟布鲁斯·巴格斯伯格分手了吗
Apparently,Bruce still has his baby fangs,and it freaks Sheila out.
很显然 布鲁斯的獠牙还在 这吓坏了席拉
And you know about Tess and Jackson?
你知道苔丝和杰克逊吗
Each was afraid that they're gonna be the ones to get dumped,
他们都很害怕自己将会被大家抛弃
so they started this really weird rumor. I can't really remember...
所以他们开始散布这些奇怪的谣言 我真的不记得
Natalie? Do you take gossip requests?
娜塔莉 你对流言作出回应了吗
Mia Rinaldi over there,is she new?
米娅·瑞娜蒂在那里 她是新人吗
Well,she's been around,but new haircut,new fangs,
她一直都在这 只是换了新发型 新的尖牙
and now she's hanging out with all the royals.
还和各个贵族混在一起
Rose Hathaway,what are you doing here?
萝丝·海瑟薇 你在这干什么
Surely you would not deprive a girl of her religious needs?
你一定不会禁止一个小女孩的宗教需要吧？
Just get inside.
快回到屋里去
The debate team,and I don't really know if I...
关于那个辩论队 我真的不知道自己是否
Speaking of extracurricular activities that I miss,is that Jesse?
说到我错过的那个课外活动 那是杰西吗？
The hot get hotter.
他比以前更惹火了
Yeah,Jesse's still the academy's number one wet dreamboat.
是啊 杰西依旧是学院里数一数二的白马王子
He has a terrible personality.
他的人品很差
Jesse has a personality?
他有人品？
I didn't know.
我不知道
Don't judge a book by its content.
不要以貌取人
You know this is a church,right?
这里是个教堂 别忘了
Gosh,if only there was a way
天啊 要是有个方法
that we could set up a double date with Ray over there.
能让我们和雷来个三人约会 那该多好
You can't tell me that there's no inbreeding amongst you royals.
你不能肯定那些贵族跟你没有血缘关系
Exhibit Ray.
尤其是闷不吭声的雷
Ray just doesn't know how to express his feelings.
他只是不知道该怎么表达自己的感情
You know,when a boy throws sand in a girl's face,
你知道 当一个男孩对一个女孩捣乱时
it really means that...
那就意味着
Never mind.
当我没说
Yeah.
走吧
- Your friend's a tool. - Don't change the subject.
- 你在利用你朋友 - 不要转移话题
You,me... you and me.
你 我 你和我
Yeah,but don't you have a girlfriend?
对 但你不是已经有女朋友了吗
- Probably. - Oh,you are bad.
- 或许吧 - 噢 你太坏了
What's so bad about bad?
有多坏？
You do understand,Rose,that even the walls of a church
你一定知道 即使是教堂的墙
can't protect a true sinner from a good lightning bolt?
也不能保护罪人逃过闪电的惩罚
Save a seat for me in the Dhampir section,you dork.
帮我在拜尔区留个座 蠢蛋
Mason likes you so much.
梅森是这么喜欢你
Why can't you go outwith a nice,funny guy like him?
你为什么不能跟他这样人好又风趣的家伙在一起呢
I know. If only I could put Mason into Jesse's body.
我知道 要是能把梅森的头脑和杰西的身体结合就好了
God can be cruel.
上帝如此残酷
Yes. That's true.
是 确实如此
Come on. Let's go.
走 走吧
Following God's path is never easy.
跟随神的脚步绝不是简单的事
Even St. Vladimir had difficulty controlling
即使是圣弗拉迪米尔也很难支配
and understanding his powers.
和理解他的力量
But he was bound to a loving Dhampir guardian
但他一定是个忠诚的拜尔族保护者
who always knew what was in his heart and mind.
知道心中所想所念的是什么
Shadow-kissed Anna.
影吻的安娜
Shadow-kissed Rose,
影吻的萝丝
you're bound to Lissa,and it's up to you to help her.
你和莉萨有联结 由你来帮助她
What's so funny? Did you write that?
你们笑什么 那是你们写的吗
Down,Dhampir,you saw me in church.
不是 拜尔人 你看到我在教堂里的
Listen,Gap Kids,if I find out
你给我听着 如果让我发现
that you had anything to do with that,I will rip your...
你和那有一点关系 我会撕破你的
You'll what? You're on lockdown. You breathe the wrong way
你会怎么样 你被关了禁闭 你跟我们不是一路人
and you're out on the pavement doing amateur blood whore porn.
你还在大庭广众之下干着业余的血妓的勾当
Listen up,that's enough excitement for a Sunday night.
听着 今天晚上的活动已经结束了
Everyone back to your dorms until further notice.
每个人都回到各自的房间 没有通知不许出来
Royal rec room,high noon. I've changed my mind.
贵族娱乐室 正午见 我改变主意了
I'm feeling bad.
我感觉不妙
Good.
到时候见
We Moroi may not burst into flames like Strigoi,
我们莫里人不会像血族人一样化为灰烬
but daylight still stings.
但光照一样会造成伤害
Poor thing.
可怜虫
Did you have jobs out in the world?
你在外面的世界有工作吗
What about an iPhone?
iPhone呢？
- What's a hashtag? - Please,stop talking.
- 主题标签是什么？- 别说话了 好吗
Whoa,horsey,what do you think you're doing?
喔 太胡来了 你在干什么
Come on,Rose. A bite while you're going at it is the best.
别害怕 萝丝 这时候咬上一口感觉棒极了
Stop it!
停下
Oh... I know that look. You've done it before.
喔 我见过这个表情 你之前也这样
I would never let a guy degrade me like that.
我绝不会让人这样作践我
Not a guy,of course. Lissa.
当然不是一个人 莉萨
We've all been wondering how she fed.
我们都在想她是怎么进食的
Once you've had fang,Rose,you never go...
一旦你有了尖牙 萝丝 你将永远不会
Daytime fraternization. Forbidden.
光天化日下交往 这是禁止的
I get it. Chill,chill.
我知道了 冷静 冷静一点
Again,Jesse? Back to your room!
又来 杰西 回你房间去
What?
什么
Lissa,what are you doing?
莉萨 你在干什么
- Rose? - Lissa's in trouble.
- 萝丝 - 莉萨遇到麻烦了
I heard... I heard a noise.
我听到 听到一些声响
Lissa...
莉萨
There's so much blood.
那儿流了好多血
It's starting again,isn't it?
它又开始出现了 对吗
I tried,Rose,I tried to bring it back,
我努力了 萝丝 我试着救活它
but... it was too late.
但 来不及了
Get over here and comfort her,jerk.
过来安慰她 混蛋
It's gonna be OK.
会没事的
- What the hell is Kirova doing? - She's giving Vasilisa a sedative,
- 基洛娃在搞什么鬼 - 她要给瓦西里萨注射镇定剂
and we are increasing her guardian detail.
我们会增强对她的保护
Our security system is geared to keeping Strigoi out,
我们的防御系统是为了阻止血族人进入
not dealing with teenage bullying within.
而不是处理内部小屁孩的恃强欺弱
Bullying? You really think that's all this is?
恃强欺弱 你真的以为就这样吗
- Rose... - Sorry.
- 萝丝 - 对不起
Thank you for not saying anything to Kirova about...
谢谢你没有告诉基洛娃关于
it was foolish of me to assume you'd be above such 17-year-old silliness.
我真是傻 还以为你不会像17岁小孩一样糊涂
Hmm. Hmm...
嗯 嗯
The sunlight,it's nice.
这阳光 真不错
I miss it.
我怀念它
Stupid vampire timetable.
吸血鬼的作息真乏味
The little sacrifices we make.
这是我们作出的小小牺牲
And the big ones.
还有大的
My 17-year-old silliness,that was the past.
我做的糊涂事 已经过去了
That was an hour ago.
才过去一个小时
Are you trying to tell me you're suddenly mature and responsible?
你是想告诉我 你一下子就成熟了有责任感了？
I'm trying to tell you that I want to be,I have to be.
我是想告诉你我会做到的 不得不做到
Teach me something more than doing laps.
教教我除了跑圈之外的其他东西
I know enough about running away.
我足够清楚该怎么逃跑了
And next time we meet,teach me how to fight.
下次再见面的时候 教我如何战斗
Pipe down. Let's pick up where we left off.
安静 我们接着上次的内容继续讲
After the tribunals in Romania... Mia!
在罗马尼亚的法庭之后 米娅
You're usually a lot better at passing on notes.
在传纸条上你总是胜人一筹
- Having an off-day? - Oh,no,Mr. Meisner,
- 想要点颜色看看？- 噢 不 梅森那先生
please don't read this note out loud,I beg of you.
请不要当众读纸条上的字 我求你了
"I'll bet that drama queen..."
"我敢肯定 是那个爱小题大做的女王 "
"I mean,drama princess,killed that fox herself"
"我指的是 爱小题大做的公主 自己杀了那只狐狸"
"to distract the school from her real secret."
"来转移学校对她真正秘密的怀疑"
Don't go on.
别念了
Mr. Meisner,you're being used as a tool to broadcast Mia's vile propaganda.
梅森那先生 你被米娅利用来宣传她卑鄙的言论了
Are you calling me a tool?
你把我叫作工具？
- If she's not,I will. - What was that,Hathaway?
- 就算她不这么说 我也会 - 那算什么 海瑟薇
Now I'm curious. "So,it turns out the reason"
现在我倒有兴趣了 "那么 这就说明"
"that Lissa survived so long on the outside"
"莉萨在外面能活了这么久"
"is she used Rose as a personal feed bag."
"是因为她把萝丝当做私人的饲料袋"
Settle down!
安静下来
Dhampir-Moroi mastication is a very serious allegation.
拜尔人和莫里人之间的私下喂食是一个非常严重的指控
I'm gonna pretend I never read this.
我会当作我从来没读过它
Everyone turn to page three of your handout.
大家把课本翻到第三页
But,Mr. Meisner,you left out the best part.
可是 梅森那先生 你漏掉了最精彩的部分
About me and my boy,Jesse,and that Dhamp tramp last night.
关于我和我的伙伴 杰西 还有拜尔流浪者发生在昨晚的事
- What? - Truth hurts,blood whore.
- 你说什么 - 戳到痛处了吧 血妓
Christian,cut it out!
克里斯琴 停下来
Kindly report to Headmistress Kirova's office,Mr. Ozera.
奥泽拉先生 去基洛娃校长的办公室好好做个检讨
- Down the hall,turn left. - Like I need directions.
- 在大厅里 左转 - 不用你告诉我
Lissa,Lissa,wait up.
莉萨 莉萨 等等
Not here,not in front of everyone.
别在这儿 当着大家的面
What was that back there? Fire magic in class?
刚刚那是什么 在课堂上施放火焰魔法？
- Uh-oh. Lovers' quarrel. - Rose,I bleed for you.
- 哦哦 小情人吵架了 - 萝丝 我的心在为你滴血
No,it's Rose who does the bleeding.
不 萝丝才是流血的那个人
You can't beat up everyone we have a problem with!
你总不能挨个揍翻 跟我们作对的人吧
- Well,I can try. - What is going on?
- 我倒想试试 - 发生了什么
I told you,Jesse and I barely even made out,and Ray wasn't even there,
我告诉过你 杰西和我什么也没发生 雷也不在那里
so I don't even know what he's talking about.
所以我根本不知道他在说些什么
OK,yes. Teenage boys are weak and sweaty piglets.
是 十几岁的男孩就像软弱好动的小猪
It is our covenant... I'm talking about you and me.
这是我们的誓约 我说的是你跟我
How did they find out about the feeding?
他们怎么知道我吸你血的事情
You know,when Jesse's fangs came poking out,did you...
你想想 当杰西的尖牙伸出来的时候 你有没有
No,not even.
没 根本不可能
But... he did kind of suspect.
但 他确实起了疑心
Lissa,let me explain,please! Let me talk...
莉萨 听我解释 让我说清楚
Is it true?
那是真的吗
You're gonna have to be more specific,Mason.
你说清楚指的是什么 梅森
Jesse and Ray,and not just hooking up,fanging up.
杰西和雷 不仅仅是瞎起哄
- They claim they fed while... - Absolutely not...
- 他们说在他们在吸血 - 绝对没有
Well,actually,Jesse and I did make out a little,but...
好吧 事实上 杰西和我确实发生了一些什么 但是
- Where there's smoke,there's fire. - Leave fire out of this.
- 果然 无风不起浪 - 别提这件事了
You girls throw yourselves at any douche bag
你们女生总是让自己跟讨厌鬼纠缠在一起
who happens to be Moroi and royal.
而那些人又恰巧是莫里族的贵族
Whoa,Duckie. I do not have time to deal with your feelings right now.
噢 可笑 我现在可没时间对付你的多愁伤感
OK.
好了
Oh,God,come on,Lissa-vision. Where are you when I need you?
该死 赶紧让我感受莉萨的处境 这时候怎么又不灵了
You should thank me for changing the news cycle.
你该谢谢我帮你转移了大家的关注焦点
It took something epic to take animal death and blood whoring
花了不少功夫才让死狐狸和血妓的事
off the Vampire Academy front page.
在学院里淡去
Please don't say "Vampire Academy."
别提 吸血鬼学院
I find the term to be quite...
我觉得这词听起来这么
You set someone on fire!
你把雷点着了
Come on. Did you see any burn marks on him?
得了吧 你看到他被烧伤了吗
Now whoever killed that fox is going to feel the real heat.
只有杀了那只狐狸的真凶才会被烧伤
Is this your idea of chivalry?
这就是你的骑士精神？
You did not just flip your hair back.
别再拨弄你的头发了
That's your move. She's flirting,folks.
你该行动了 她在挑逗你 伙计
If we used our magic as a weapon,
如果我们把魔法当做武器
instead of just for warm and fuzzy classroom exercises,
而不是为了取暖或者愚蠢的课堂活动
the Strigoi wouldn't be picking us off.
血族人就不能拿我们怎么样了
- Yes,but the rules forbid... - The rules?
- 你说的对 但是规矩禁止 - 规矩？
Lissa,I've seen the way you tilt your head from time to time.
莉萨 我已经看到你甩你的头发很多次了
I'm very sure I don't know what you're talking about.
我根本不知道你在说什么
Hey,compulsion must have been a necessity in the outside world.
嘿 强迫术在外面的世界肯定必不可少
You can't know all my secrets. Yet.
你不可能这么了解我的事情 目前为止
Queen Tatiana?
塔提安娜女王？
I hope I did not take you too much by surprise,
我希望这不会让你们感到惊讶
but sometimes your queen awakens with a need to look upon her lovelies.
但有时候你们的女王醒来的时候总想看看她可爱的孩子们
Where's Vasilisa?
瓦西里萨在哪里
Vasilisa Dragomir?
瓦西里萨·德拉古米尔？
Please come up and let me see the princess.
快上来 让我好好看看我的公主
Not a day goes by where we don't lament
我们永远哀悼
the loss of your parents and your brother.
你父母和你的兄弟的不幸去世
The Dragomir name represents the finest of Moroi qualities.
德拉古米尔这个名字代表着莫里族最优秀的品质
While you,Vasilisa Dragomir,
而你 瓦西里萨·德拉古米尔
the last of the Dragomir line...
德拉古米尔家族中的最后一人
if you are our future,I am less than impressed.
如果你就是我们未来的希望 我将大为失望
The power that comes from royal blood must be used responsibly.
来自贵族血统的力量应该有所担当
While you... you give us dead animals,blood games,
而你 你给我们带来的是死狐狸 鲜血的游戏
escapes to Oregon. Shameful!
私逃到俄勒冈 真可耻
- Queen Tatiana,I can explain. - Shh,shh,shh.
- 塔提安娜女王 听我解释 - 嘘
Not now,dear.
别急 亲爱的
However,I have every confidence
然而 我有足够的信心
that our dear Vasilisa will turn things around.
我们亲爱的Vasilisa会改变这一切
Now,let us adjourn to the banquet hall.
现在 大会结束 让我们到礼堂的宴会上去吧
My father would never have done something like that.
换做我的父亲是绝不会这么说的
After all that Lissa has been through,to be shamed by our queen bee?
莉萨经历了这么多 结果被我们的女蜂王羞辱？
Don't you mean queen bee-etch?
你该不会是想说女疯王吧
You don't talk to Lissa like that.
你可别对莉萨这么说
So much for round-the-clock guardians.
守护者还真是夜以继日的干活
Lissa?
莉萨
Oh,my God.
噢 天哪
- By the soul of St. Vladimir. - Who would do something like this? Why?
- 看在圣弗拉迪米尔的面上 - 这是谁干的 为什么
Go to the wall,Nat. Talk to me.
去看看情况 奈特 再告诉我
What?
什么
Yeah,OK.
好吧
Oh,God.
噢 天啊
It's fresh,and it's Moroi.
血还是新鲜的 是莫里族人干的
OK,can you tell me if it's royal?
好 你能尝出是不是贵族的血吗
- Don't be absurd. - Said the girl licking the wall.
- 别开玩笑了 - 你都已经对着墙舔了
I can tell you it's more than one person's blood.
我能告诉你这不只是一个人的血
They misspelled "beware."
他们拼错了"小心点"
Lissa,I can clean it up. I'm sorry.
莉萨 我会打扫干净的 对不起
Leave it. The misspelling shows it was just a bunch of stupid teenagers.
别管它了 拼写都错了 说明是一群蠢小子干的
OK,you know what,I'm gonna go start packing. I'm really...
好了 你知道吗 我打算去收拾东西了 我实在
No,Rose. We can't just keep running away,at least until we know
别 萝丝 我们不能总是逃避 至少要弄清
what we're running away from.
我们在逃避什么
Ooh! A mystery,how exciting.
喔 神秘探险 真刺激
We can be like three Nancy Drews trying...
我们可以像三个少女妙探一样去
I hate mysteries. I would prefer a good Strigoi attack at this point
我讨厌谜团 我宁愿一个善战的血族人来攻击
because at least I'd know what those homicidal bloodsuckers want.
至少我知道这些嗜杀成性的吸血鬼目的是什么
No more. I am taking our dear beloved queen's advice,
再也不会这样了 我要听取敬爱的女王的建议
and I'm turning things around.
我会改变这些事情的
Jesse and Ray are pawns. Mia is the mastermind.
杰西和雷只是帮凶 米娅才是主使
Yeah,but we didn't even really know Mini-Mia
嗯 但我们根本还不了解小米娅
when we were compelled to leave for the first time.
在我们第一次被迫逃跑的时候
Ms. Karp is the one that we should be focused on.
我们该关注卡普女士才对
Do what you have to do,Dhampir. I am done trying to crawl under the radar.
想做什么随你吧 我已经受够了被他们摆弄了
It's not possible,and... it's not effective.
那不太可能 也 也不奏效
Besides,I have a way of getting people to see my side of the story.
此外 我想到一个办法让大家都关注到我身上来
Don't worry,Natalie knows of my skills.
别担心 娜塔莉知道我的能力
It was too exhausting keeping it from her.
要瞒住她太难了
Are you going to use compulsion on Mia?
你要对米娅用强迫术吗
Where's the fun in that?
那有什么意思
I'm going to use compulsion on everyone but Mia.
我要对除了她之外的所有人用强迫术
But compulsion on such a large scale...
但是要对这么多人施展强迫术
Magic should be used for something more than warm and fuzzy classroom exercises.
魔法不应该只用在取暖或者愚蠢的课堂活动上
Oh,God,and now you're quoting Christian?
噢 天啊 你倒引用起克里斯琴的话来了
- What? - Yeah,I was there.
- 什么 - 对 那时我在你脑子里
And the poison that that freak
那个怪人给你灌输的坏想法
is pumping into your brain makes me want to vomit.
让我感到恶心
Lissa,I'm the reckless,and you're the cautious,remember?
莉萨 我是冒失鬼 而你才是做事谨慎的那个 忘了吗
You've already taken too many hits for me,Rose.
你已经为我承担太多了 萝丝
Look,it's your turn to have a little cry,
听着 这回该轮到我保护你了
and it's my turn to kick a little ass.
由我去解决这些事情
Whoa!
喔
You do not jump out at a guardian like that.
你不要像个守护者一样跳出来
I think you mean novice.
我想你说的应该是新来的守护者吧
Just wanted to know if Lissa was all right.
我只想看看莉萨是不是还好
Queen Tatiana had no right to bring up family.
塔提安娜女王没有权利再提起她的家人
- I should go and talk to Lissa. - Oh,don't worry about it.
- 我该去和莉萨谈谈 - 别 不劳你费心了
But I do. Lissa and I have a bond.
我确实担心她 莉萨和我有联结
A bond?
联结？
Listen,Chris,just stay away from her.
听着 克里斯 离她远一点
She's had her little flirtation with the dark side,and she's done.
她不为人知的一面稍稍挑逗了你 但那已经过去了
Lissa used to like Hot Topic,too,and then she turned 12.
莉萨以前也喜欢热门话题那样的思想 直到她12岁那年
I was only concerned.
我只是出于关心
There's a fine line between concerned and stalker.
关心和暗恋大不相同
Seriously,Christian,go away.
说真的 克里斯琴 你走吧
It's what Lissa wants.
莉萨也希望这样
OK.
好吧
I thought we'd practice out here,away from there.
我希望我们在这里训练 离那儿远点
Dimitri,I know you must have heard some rumors.
迪米特里 我知道你一定听到了一些流言
All that high-school der'mo stays back there,not here.
所有拜尔族和莫里族的高中生都待在学院里 而不是这
This is life and death.
这就是生存和死亡的区别
The silver. Don't be afraid of it.
银锥 不要害怕它
Besides the sun,this stake is your only friend against the Strigoi.
除了太阳之外 银锥是你对抗血族唯一的利器
But you must subdue the monster and bring yourself to kill.
但你必须先制服 才能杀死他们
Yeah,killing Strigoi is what it's all about,right?
嗯 杀死血族是它的最终目的 对吧
Most Strigoi were once Moroi.
绝大多数血族人曾经都是莫里族的
Some turn themselves Strigoi by killing during the feeding process.
一些莫里族人在进食的时候杀死供给者 从而变成血族
But many are turned by force.
但多数都是被迫转变的
If you are going to thrust,thrust.
如果你要下手 那就果断点
My point is you might have known one personally,as a friend.
我的意思是 你可能认识对方
Can you kill someone you used to know?
你能杀死你曾经认识的人吗
I... If it was them or me or Lissa...
我 如果是他们 还是我 或者莉萨
You hesitate,and that hesitation could kill you.
你迟疑了 而迟疑会置你于死地
You have to keep telling yourself that they aren't the same people you knew.
你必须不断提醒自己 他们已经不是你熟识的人了
Good. Very good.
不错 很好
I don't mean to belittle what you are going through.
我并没有贬低你经历的事情
The queen crossed a line.
女王太过分了
But the Dhampir must always bow down. I get it. The Moroi come first.
但拜尔族注定俯首称臣 我知道的 莫尔族至高无上
Not always. My father was a Moroi.
并非如此 我的父亲以前是莫里族
He visited Russia once a year.
他每年都来俄罗斯
He liked to hit my mother.
他总喜欢殴打我母亲
When I was old enough,I liked to hit him.
当我足够大了 我就开始反抗他
He stopped visiting.
他就再也没来过了
- How old is old enough? - Ten.
- 多大算足够大 - 10岁
The only parent I've ever really had is the academy.
我真正的父母亲是这个学院
Your mother is one of the most feared
你的母亲是世界上最受人惧怕
and respected Dhampir guardians in the world.
和尊敬的拜尔族守护者之一
I see you finally read her telegram.
我看到你最后读了她的电报
You want to know what it said?
你想知道上面写了什么吗
"Glad you're alive. What you did was inexcusable. Mom."
"很欣慰你还活着 不过你的所作所为真是不可原谅 妈妈"
Aw.
喔
What do you know of your Moroi father?
你对你莫里族的父亲了解多少
That he must have had dark eyes and amazing hair.
他的眼睛一定是深色的 还有漂亮的头发
When I start killing Strigoi left and right,
当我能够轻易杀死血族人的时候
I'm gonna have to cut it all off,won't I?
我打算把头发全给剪了 说到做到
Sorry. That sounded really girly.
不好意思 听起来太小女生了
You can wear it up.
你该留起来
Doesn't a Dhampir need to keep their molnija marks exposed?
拜耳族人不是应该把他们的标记露出来吗
Don't ever cut your hair. Wear it up.
千万不要剪掉你的头发 蓄起来
You have to admire our queen.
你不得不尊敬我们的女王
Her elegance,her dignity,her ability to recognize trash.
她的典雅 她的尊贵 她一眼就看出谁是废材的能力
And my good mood is over.
我已经没有耐心了
You know,"beware" isn't spelled with an "H" in it.
你知道吗 "当心"这个词中没有H
- Hey. - Where's Lissa?
- 嘿 - 莉萨在哪里
I haven't seen her,but guess what?
我一直没看到她 但你猜怎么着
I heard that Mia and Aaron are going
我听说米娅和阿伦要去
on that field trip to the hemoglobin factory.
血红素工厂进行考察旅行
I figured it gives us a chance to raid their rooms...
我觉得这是给我们机会去查查他们的房间
- Pretend to be talking to me. - But I am talking to you.
- 装作在跟我说话 - 我不是正在跟你说嘛
It's nasty. If you guys were doing it,
这真是太恶心了 如果你们真的那样的话
I'm not surprised Rose got addicted and necked with Jesse.
我并不惊讶萝丝喜欢杰西还和他搞上了
She didn't do it with Jesse.
她跟杰西并没有怎么样
And it's not like we fornicated. We just didn't have any feeders.
而且跟他家私下说的不一样 我们没有什么供给者
It's no big deal,Camilla.
没什么大不了的 卡米拉
Yeah,it's no big deal. I mean,Jesse's a liar.
对 没什么大不了的 我是说 杰西是个骗子
What are you guys doing tonight?
你们今晚打算干什么
Shannon and I are going to her room to study for Meisner's test.
香农跟我打算去她的房间准备梅森那的考试
Invite me.
邀请我
Lissa,you want to study with us tonight?
莉萨 你今晚想跟我们一起复习吗
Sure.
当然
Oh,look. It's the queen's court jester.
噢 快看 是女王会上嘲笑的那家伙
You can't talk to me like that.
你没资格那么说我
The queen treats me like a daughter,so you should be envious.
女王待我如女儿 你该感到嫉妒
You're buds with Mia. What secrets are you keeping?
你是米娅的跟屁虫 你藏了什么秘密
- I like to wear my mommy's knick... - Not about you.
- 我喜欢穿我妈妈的内裤 - 不要关于你的
Secrets about Mia.
而是关于米娅的秘密
- Busted. - Ow.
- 失败了吧 - 喔
Did you witness how amazing I was?
你看到我多厉害了吧
I felt it. Using the power has an effect,a cost,
我感觉到了 使用那个魔法会有有影响 一种损耗
on both of us.
我们两个人都是
Look at you,you're shaking. I'm shaking.
看看你自己 你在发颤 我也是
Three cups of coffee shaking.
来三杯手摇咖啡
More like 18 cups,dark roast,no room.
都能来18杯了 深烘焙 带走
- I got it,the computer. - What?
- 我拿到了 米娅的电脑 - 什么
I told you. Mia's on a field trip...
我告诉过你 米娅去考察旅行了
Hey,you. I'm sorry I haven't been to church in a while,but...
嘿 很抱歉我有段时间没去教堂了 但是
It's OK. You don't have to pretend anymore.
没事的 你不用再装了
You've had your little flirtation with the dark side.
你已经用你不为人知的一面挑逗过了
- Check that box and move on. - What are you talking about?
- 看看电脑里是什么 继续你的事吧 - 你在说什么
But,hey,nice hypocrisy on the magic use.
但是 听着 施展强迫术时你装的真像
So what? A stolen laptop.
那又怎么样 一台偷来的笔记本电脑而已
Kirova strangled Internet access years ago.
基洛娃很久之前就关闭了网络连接
Yeah,St. Vlad's operates on a closed network,
没错 学院一直在封闭的网络中运行
but there is more to a person than status updates.
但这更能了解一个人而不是更新状态
There's photos,receipts,inter-academy e-mails.
里面有照片 收据 学院内部的邮件等等
You're making my brain bleed.
你快把我弄疯了
But you were sure right about cuckoo Christian.
但你对克里斯琴那个怪人倒是说的挺对
What a whack job.
真是个疯子
Are you seriously going to that study group with Camilla?
你真的要去和卡米拉一起复习吗
You know,you don't have to use compulsion to be popular.
你本没必要利用强迫术来使自己受欢迎的
You may not recall,but you can be quite charming on your own.
你也许不用回想过去如何 但是你自己本来就很迷人
Who has the time? Natalie,return that computer.
我没有那闲时间 娜塔莉 把电脑还回去
Later,losers.
再见 没人宠的家伙们
Gosh.
天哪
I wish Lissa could compulse Ray into being nicer.
我希望莉萨能强迫雷让他变的好一点
And taking my virginity.
然后拿走我的初夜
No one has ever really seen me naked.
还没有谁见过我赤身裸体的样子
- Moroi,Dhampir,human,mineral. - Uh-huh.
- 莫里族 拜尔族 人类 甚至石头 都没有 - 原来如此
I once turned a plant around because I was too shy to change in front of it.
我曾经把一盆花挪开了 因为我实在不好意思在它面前换衣服
You know I can't un-hear this,right?
你知道我不能装作听不到 对吧
- Sorry. Yeah,I... - It's OK.
- 不好意思 我 - 没关系
Though I'm not much better. I'm crushing on my mentor,Dimitri,
我也好不了多少 我喜欢上我的导师迪米特里了
who's,like,old enough to be my...
他年龄大的可以当我
Not my father... like an uncle.
不是父亲 像个叔叔之类的
Like a disturbingly sexy uncle.
像个让人把持不住的性感大叔
Andre?
安德烈？
What the hell is this?
这是什么东西
Goodness gracious.
天哪 真恩爱
Andre,Andre?
安德烈 安德烈？
That's Lissa's brother,isn't it?
那是莉萨的哥哥 不是吗
Andre could have,like,any girl he wanted,and he usually did.
安德烈可以得到所有他想要的女孩 他也时常这么做
Most of the girls knew the drill. It was down low,no commitments and...
大多数女孩也知道这个情况 这发生的很低调 没人作出评论
This is the face of a girl who did not know the drill.
看着面孔 她好像还不知道实情
Holy moly.
天哪
Mia's not just angry at Lissa. She despises the whole Dragomir line.
米娅并不只是对莉萨生气 她还看不起所有拜尔族人
Right,which makes her someone willing to take things to a whole other level.
是的 正因为如此她才乐此不疲的把事情闹大
OK,all right. Take this back to Mia's room.
好了 把这个放会米娅的房间吧
- Yeah? - OK.
- 好吗 - 没问题
See ya.
回见
Hey. To what do I owe this honor?
嘿 我这是积了几辈子的德
Can we talk,Oscar?
我们聊聊吧 奥斯卡
I'm worried about Lissa.
我在担心莉萨
I love that our princess is learning that the best defense is a good offense,
我很欣慰我们的公主学会了进攻 就是最好的防守这个道理
and believe me,I am all for putting mad munchkin Mia in her place,
也要相信我 我会尽全力让疯狂的小鬼米娅不要有什么小动作
but this Operation Brainwash is turning Lissa into something she's not.
但是对大家的洗脑也让莉萨变得不像自己
She can't see that. I can.
当局者迷 而我却看得一清二楚
It's like I feel Lissa's feelings more than she does.
就像我比莉萨更能体会到她自己的感受
I need to put on my game face.
我要开始动真格了
Can't wait around for my next psychedelic flashback.
等不及要来一次迷幻回旋踢了
The stakes are too high.
风险太大了
Get it?
知道吗
Dhampir? Fight with stakes?
拜尔族 冒着风险战斗
Best defense,good offense.
一流的防守 一流的进攻
I knew you'd improve.
我发现你进步很大
No fair learning from a god.
由神一般的人教你真是不公平
I heard you were good at taking on two guys at once.
我听说你擅长以一敌二
Rose,uh,about Jesse and Ray...
萝丝 呃 关于杰西和雷的事
- Mason... - No,not that.
- 梅森 - 不 我不是要说那个
In the locker room,it was weird.
在更衣室里面 我发现了一个奇怪的现象
They had these bandages on their wrists.
他们的手腕上都缠着绷带
I don't know if it means anything.
我不知道这是不是意味着什么
Covered wrists?
缠着手腕？
- Is that some new Moroi thing? - Check out Mia.
- 这是莫里族的新特征？- 看米娅的手腕
- She's getting away. - Let her.
- 她走了 - 让她走吧
Kirova's the one I should be tracking.
我得跟踪一下基洛娃
I need to break into Kirova's office today
今天我要偷偷地到基洛娃的办公室去一下
when the fang gang is asleep,OK?
等她睡着了我就潜进去 怎么样？
There's a file in there that could be the key to my past,
她办公室里有个对我来说很重要的文件
my present and my future.
对我的过去 现在和将来都很重要
That's it?
是吗？
Sounds cool.
听起来很酷
Forty-five minutes of silence.
45分钟的沉默
It has to be a Rose Hathaway record.
这是必须做到的
OK.
好吧
What do you know about Ms. Karp?
关于卡普女士 你知道多少？
Karp? She retired before I even arrived.
卡普？她在我来这儿之前就退休了
Kirova,Victor,you.
基洛娃 维克多还有你
I ask about Karp,and it's no eye contact and a subject change.
我问的是卡普不要转换话题
Enough. Your training of late has been quite...
行了 最近你的训练都非常
- ...fine. - Fine? That's it?
- 还行 - 还行？就只是还行？
What do you want me to say?
那你还想要我说什么？
That you are a remarkable quick study?
说你掌握的非常快？
That you bring originality to classic moves?
说你在原有的动作上面有所创新？
Yeah,I want you to say all those things.
没错 我就是想要你这么说
Good night,Rose.
晚安 萝丝
What did I do wrong? I had you.
我哪儿出错了？我攻击到你了的
The battle cry was your first mistake.
你在进攻之前就不应该呐喊
I like your laugh. Singular,not plural.
我喜欢你的笑声 真稀罕
It's the first time I've heard it.
这是我第一次听到
So even if I wouldn't have screamed,you still would have stopped me,right?
所以就算我攻击你之前 没有大喊你还是会拿下我的 是吗？
Probably,but nice initiative.
可能吧 但是这是一个很好的开端
Keep trying those surprise attacks. It's good training for both of us.
继续尝试这种突然袭击 这对我们俩都是一种很好的训练
So,uh... you have any other moves you want to show me?
所以呢 你还有什么要向我展示的吗？
I give it and they take it,but when it comes back,it's not the same,is it?
我把东西给了他们 但是当他们还给我的时候东西就不一样了
I give it and they take it,
我把东西交给了他们并且他们也拿到了
but when it comes back,it's not the same,is it?
但是东西还给我的时候却不一样了
They're coming to get me.
他正要过来找我
But they want something that I can't give them.
但是他想要从我这儿拿走一样我不能给的东西
Those of us who never declared,those of us who have powers that have no name,
我们中间那些有力量而又不张扬的人默默无闻
there's only so much we can do,only so much we can handle.
我们能做的有限 只能做这么多
I should have gone with Vasilisa. I should have.
我应该要和瓦西里萨一起走的 应该要这样的
I'm so alone.
现在我感觉很孤单
The clarity of the darkness beckons.
尤其是在黑暗的夜晚
I just want it to go away,the shaking,
我只是想远离身体的颤抖
the scratching,nightmares,all go away.
远离折磨 远离噩梦
Lissa. The king and queen of the school together again,
莉萨 学院的国王和王后重归于好了
- the way it should be. - Lissa!
- 他们本来就该在一起 - 莉萨
It's you and I who are destined to be together.
你和我才是命中注定要在一起的
Let me handle this.
让我来处理
Look at what you made me do to myself,just like my damn parents.
看看你都让我成什么样了 就像是我的混账父母
Lissa!
莉萨
I have a new family now.
现在我有了一个新的家庭
Strigoi brothers and sisters,attack!
血族的兄弟姐妹们 动手
- Rose,what's happening? - Stay close,right behind me,
- 萝丝 这是怎么回事？- 跟着我 跟紧点
just like we practiced.
就像我们之前练习的那样
OK. It's not looking great,
好吧 虽然看起来情况不妙
but we will get through this,Lissa,we always do.
但是我们能搞定的 莉萨 我们可以的
Dimitri?
迪米特里？
Oh,Rose,you worry too much.
萝丝 你担心得太多了
Lissa,no.
莉萨 不
What are friends for?
真正的朋友是怎样的？
No.
不
No!
不要
Rose,are you there?
萝丝 你在吗？
Did you feel that one?
你感应到了吗？
What a weird dream.
好奇怪的梦啊
Yeah. Yeah,Liss,weird dream.
是啊 是啊 莉丝 奇怪的梦
Don't you dare feel sorry for me.
难道你胆敢不觉得有愧于我
Feel sorry for her,for the princess.
有愧于公主吗？
I lied.
我骗了你
Lissa doesn't think that you're a creepy stalker.
莉萨并没有觉得你是一个阴暗的跟踪狂
She actually likes you.
事实上她是喜欢你的
Then why did you...?
那为什么当初你说
Because I think that you're a creepy stalker,
因为我认为你是一个阴暗的跟踪狂
and I actually don't like you,but...
并且我真的很不喜欢你 只不过
I like the way that Lissa feels when she's around you.
莉萨跟你在一起时她的那种感觉是我喜欢的
So what?
所以呢？
Look at her. She's back on top.
你看 她已经走出了低谷
She's not happy. She's not herself,not as she wants to be.
她并不开心 那不是真正的她 那不是她想要的
Trust me,I know,Christian.
相信我 我了解她 克里斯琴
I can f...
我可以
Shadow-kissed Anna did all she could,
影吻的安娜已经尽力了
but on some days,Satan's darkness
但是 不知什么时候 撒旦的黑暗势力
seeped into St. Vladimir,weakening his health and mind.
已经潜入了圣弗拉迪米尔 不断吞噬他的健康和灵魂
See,Christian,I don't want that to be Lissa.
你知道吗 克里斯琴 我不希望莉萨那样
You are the phantom here.You must know
你是这儿的幻灵 你一定知道
where they keep the books and scrolls
他们把那些书籍 卷轴之类的东西放哪儿了
and whatnot,and I need to figure out what her abilities...
我需要知道她到底有些什么力量
You sabotaged the first good thing to happen to me in a long time,
你坏了我这么久以来的第一件好事
and now you want me to help you?
现在你还指望着让我帮你？
Ugh. God.
额 天啊
Princess party in the royal rec room.
公主的派对在皇家娱乐室
There's my blood bitch. What took you so long?
我的人肉血袋 怎么这么久才来？
It's great that you can joke about it.
很高兴你们能这样开玩笑
Lissa,listen. A lot has happened.
莉萨 听着 最近发生了很多事情
We have to sit down and have a real conversation.
我们必须坐下来好好谈谈
Stop being so serious,Rose. It's a party.
别这么严肃嘛 这是在开派对
- Hey,Natalie. - Hi.
- 嗨 娜塔莉 - 嗨
Awesome party,huh?
很棒的派对
Check this.
看着
Can you say "keg magic"?
你能说这是"小魔术"吗？
Wow,Lissa,you can really do it all.
哇 莉萨 你无所不能
Well,of course I can. I'm the princess.
当然啦 我可是公主
But doing it all is wrong,right?
但是无所不为是不对的 对吗？
Fire,air,fire,air,fire,
火 气 火 气 火
air,fire,air,
气 火 气
- fire... - Hey.
火 嘿
Aaron.
阿伦
Rose! Where are you going?
萝丝 你要去哪儿？
You weren't just going to bail without saying goodbye.
你不能不辞而别
I need to go home and sleep you off.
我要回家 通过睡觉摆脱你
Oh,is the bond making you as buzzed as I am?
是我们之间特别的联系让你和我一样兴奋吗？
God,you are burning us both out on magic.
天啊 你的魔法让我们俩都累到不行
Stop worrying. It's working.
不用担心
Weeks have gone by,and Mia is toast.
很多周过去了 米娅广受赞誉
No threats,no notes,no foxes.
没有威胁 不需要格外小心 也没有欺骗
You're just bummed that I,not you,have neutralized the threat.
你只是因为是我化解了那个威胁而不是你 所以感到不高兴
You neutralized a threat,not "the" threat.
你是化解了一个威胁 但不是那个威胁
And Aaron,seriously,
阿伦 你坦白告诉我
you really want to show up to the Equinox Dance with that?
你真的想要跟那人跳舞吗？
He's... cute.
他 很可爱
And incredibly boring.
并且很无聊
You think everyone's boring.
所有人在你眼里都很无聊
Christian's not.
克里斯琴不是
No,you were right about him.
不对 你喜欢他
I knew "little flirtation with the dark side" sounded like one of your lines.
我知道"用不为人知的一面挑逗"是你喜欢的作风
- Sorry. - You know what? You can have Christian.
对不起 你知道吗？你可以跟克里斯琴在一起的
You're both savages.
你们两个都是野蛮人
Lissa,what I've been trying to tell you
莉萨 我一直都想要告诉你
is that you're making this about high school,
从高中的时候你就这样觉得
and it's about something more.
但是事情并不是你想的这么简单
Natalie... Are you nuts? What are you thinking?
娜塔莉 你疯了吗？你想干什么？
Trust me,you do not want to have to get a nose job in Montana!
相信我 你不会想要在蒙塔纳给鼻子动手术的
Sorry. I'm sorry. It's...
对不起 对不起 只是
When you both left the party,I had no one to...
你们俩都离开派对之后我就没人说话了
Everyone kept staring at me,so I left,
所有人都开始盯着我看 于是我就离开了
and on my way back to the dorms,I swear,someone...
并且在回宿舍的路上 我发誓有人
more like something,started to follow me.
不对 是什么东西 在跟踪我
I just... I don't know. I'm probably just being paranoid.
我只是 我也不知道 也许是我多疑了吧
That's not paranoia.
那不是多疑
- That's a psi-hound. - Rose thinks everything is a psi-hound.
- 那是恶灵犬 - 在萝丝看来一切都是恶灵犬
What's a psi-hound?
什么是恶灵犬？
- What's my backpack doing over there? - Lissa,no.
- 我的背包怎么在那儿？- 莉萨 别过去
Lissa!
莉萨
Oscar! Oh,my God.
奥斯卡 噢 天啊
Oscar.
奥斯卡
- Lissa,just... - No,Rose!
- 莉萨 听我 - 别说了萝丝
Shadow-kissed Rose,you're bound to Lissa,
影吻的萝丝 你和莉萨联结着
and it's up to you to help her.
保护她是你的职责
Don't you understand?
你明白吗？
The more that Lissa uses her powers,the worse it'll get.
莉萨力量用得越多 情况就会越糟
The more dangerous it will be.
她就会越危险
They came for me. They'll come for her.
现在他们要过来抓我 将来他们就会去抓她的
What are you talking about? Is it the Strigoi?
你说的是什么？他们是指血族吗？
This isn't about Strigoi.
这跟血族无关
Not everything to be feared roams outside the gates of St. Vladimir's.
并不是所有恐怖的事情都只会发生在圣弗拉迪米尔外面
- I don't understand. - Oh,you couldn't understand it.
- 我不明白 - 你是理解不了的
You don't have to understand. Look at me.
你也不需要弄明白 看着我
No,please,Ms. Karp,not compulsion,please.
不 拜托 卡普女士 不要对我施强迫术
- I beg of you,please! - I'm not taking your memories away.
- 求你了 - 我不是要抹掉你的记忆
Just hiding them for a bit.
我只是将它们部分隐藏
Lissa's life is in peril.
莉萨正处于危险之中
You only need to know you have to get her away from the academy.
你唯一要做的就是把她从学校救出来
Forget everything I've said until it's time not to forget.
你只需要在必要的时候记得我说过的话
I guess you could say that it was half-repression
你可能会说那是半抑郁和
and half-compulsion,and when you asked me
半强迫 如果你问我
why we left the academy in the first place,
为什么一开始我们就要离开学校
a part of me couldn't remember.
我也不完全清楚
I just knew that we had to get out.
我只知道我们必须离开
Outrageous.
一派胡言
What Headmistress Kirova means to say
基洛娃校长的意思是说
is that it was brave of you to come forward,Rose.
你这样做勇气可嘉 萝丝
Well,I'm doing it for Lissa. She needs help.
我所做的都是为了莉萨 她需要我的帮助
But is it really true she can bring the dead to life?
但是她真的能起死回生的能耐吗？
Dead's dead... but from the brink of death.
死了就是死了 除非只是在死亡边缘的人
Not since St. Vladimir,and he never declared a magic,either.
就连圣弗拉迪米尔都从没真正精通过魔法
But there is no actual proof to anything you're saying.
但是你所说的都是无凭无据的
We found no cameras,and the compulsion alone
我们没有看到任何的照片 就只有你说的强迫术
can only be done in specific environments by trained professionals.
能够由训练过的专员在特定的环境中施行
Well,Lissa had no problem doing it to you,right in your own office.
莉萨完全可以对你施强迫术 就在你办公室里面
Surely,you had to wonder why you didn't just throw me out of school.
你肯定有想过为什么你没直接把我赶出学校
It's outrageous.
荒唐
Enough,please.
够了 请
Ms. Sonya Karp. I want to see the Day Six footage.
桑娅·卡普女士 我想要看到"第六天"的片段
I've had a rough night.
我已经有过一个难熬的夜晚
Don't make me crawl through a ventilator shaft
不要逼我通过爬通风管
and lower myself down into the security center on a wire.
来到安全中心
Headmistress,we have no right to keep Rose in the dark for as long as we have.
校长 我们没有权利一直隐瞒萝丝
All right. All right.
好吧 好吧
Take her downstairs. Show her everything.
带她下楼 把一切都告诉她
Show us Karp Day Six,please. Thank you.
麻烦给我们播放卡普的"第六天" 谢谢
I knew this is what you were looking for.
我知道这就是你一直在找的
Couple months after you left,Ms. Karp had a complete breakdown.
在你离开后的几个月 卡普女士彻底崩溃了
And did the doctors find a way to help her?
医生有想到办法帮她吗？
She found a way to help herself.
她自己想到了一个帮助自己的办法
Karp was not like the others.
卡普和其他的拜尔族成员不同
She didn't become Strigoi for the power or the immortality.
她不是为了力量或者永生而变成血族
She just... wanted the pain to go away.
她只是 想要摆脱痛苦
Nobody likes to talk about it,but the most effective way
没有人愿意提起这个方法
for the undeclared to take away their special anxiety
但是对于年轻的拜尔族成员来说 最有效的摆脱焦虑的方法
is for them to take a life and become Strigoi.
就是咬一个人然后让自己变成血族
Strigoi have an inner clarity.
血族有一个内在的特性
No feelings. No worries.
冷血 无惧
No weakness.
残酷
She got away.
她离开了医院
We don't know where she is now.
我们不知道她现在在哪儿
Roza? Roza,calm down.
萝丝？萝丝 冷静点
- I'll protect you. - Roza?
- 我会保护你的 - 萝丝？
It's not Karp. It's Lissa.
不是因为卡普 是因为莉萨
She's upstairs,and she's... she's pissed.
她在楼上 并且她很生气
Cuts on my arm? Is that what she said?
我手臂上有伤痕？她是这么说的吗？
And without the use of a blade,no less.
如果不是用刀片划的 就没有别的了
I know I've been having trouble declaring a magic,
我知道我一直在费劲地解释一个魔法
but that seems a pretty pointless skill.
但是这似乎没什么大不了的
Allow me to put your mind at ease.
让我轻松地控制你的思维
Rose is a dear friend,but she has a talent for tall tales.
萝丝是一个很好的朋友 但是她很会吹牛
Kirova's letting herself be compulsed even after I gave the compulsion speech!
虽然我跟基洛娃说了强迫术 但她还是让别人给自己施了法
It's classic! Ever since the accident,
可笑 从那次事件之后
it's like my life has been on autopilot.
我的生活就像是被安装了自动驾驶仪
I guess in Ms. Karp's own spooky way,she was trying
根据卡普女士一贯的奇怪作风 我猜她是尝试着
to help me figure it all out,but who do I have now?
帮我理清一切 但是现在我还能相信谁？
There is another person who can help you.
还有一个人能帮你
He is on our flags,posters,uniforms
在我们的校旗 海报 校服
and the statue in the middle of the school.
和学校中间的雕像上都可以看到他
St. Vladimir?
圣弗拉迪米尔？
OK. I'm on it.
好 我懂了
So,is this where the outcast losers hang out?
所以 这就是被抛弃的失败者出没的地方？
- How did you know...? - Books on St. Vladimir. Now.
- 你是怎么知道 - 圣弗拉迪米尔说的
Before,I was asking. This is me telling.
在我提问之前 先听我说
- God,you're annoying. - I'm right that this could help Lissa.
- 天啊 你真的很烦人 - 我相信这能帮到莉萨
Yeah. That's what's so annoying. Come on.
是的 这正是烦人的地方 走吧
God,what's a girl got to do to get a definition
天啊 一个女孩要怎样做才能被定义为
- of "shadow-kissed" up in this... - Check this out.
- "影吻"什么的 - 看这个
"Vladimir had mastered a very rare magic,
弗拉迪米尔掌握了一项罕见的魔法
and this magic had a name: Spirit."
这种魔法被称为灵魂魔法
All this time,Lissa's been beating herself up
一直以来莉萨都在拼命证明
about not being able to declare a magic.
自己不会魔法
Oh,my God,if she only knew.
噢 天啊 如果她知道自己有魔法会怎样
This makes Lissa more special
这会使得莉萨比我们想象中更加特别
and valuable than I ever even imagined.
更加有价值
I guess I should be happy that the bad guys aren't trying to kill Lissa,
那些坏人目的不是要杀了莉萨 我应该为此感到高兴
but it kind of just makes things more sick and disgusting.
但是这让事情变得更加奇怪和恶心
What do they want from Lissa?
他们想要从莉萨身上得到什么？
What is the point of killing her cat and setting up cameras?
他们杀掉她的猫并且安装摄像头的目的是什么？
- Who could be that cruel? - Headmistress Kirova could be.
- 谁会这么残忍？- 基洛娃校长会
And Mia likes to film her pranks.
米娅喜欢拍摄一些恶作剧
- That... - I know.
- 那 - 我知道
Both a little on the nose,but...
虽然说的没错但
No,maybe they're so obvious that they're not obvious.
不对 也许正是因为她们太明显了反而使得她们不容易被发现
I did see Kirova with Mia the other night.
不久前的一个晚上 我的确看到基洛娃和米娅一起
OK,my conspiracy theory of choice
根据我的推测我怀疑
is that someone might be trying to drive Lissa mad,
是有人想要把莉萨逼疯
to take her out of throne contention.
这样一来莉萨就不能参加王位的竞争了
I mean,we all know Queen Tatiana has her issues.
我的意思是 我们都知道塔提安娜王后的问题
All three witches could be working together.
那三个女巫得要合作起来
I like the way your mind works. Just hold that thought.
我赞成你的思维方式 继续
"At times,after the expense of power and in times of trauma,
每次施完法以及受到创伤时
Vladimir's agony would manifest directly onto his skin."
弗拉迪米尔的伤痛就会直接在皮肤上体现出来
So this proves that Lissa's not a freak.
这就证明了莉萨那是正常的
Sort of. I mean,it shows that she could be rehabilitated.
可以这么说 我的意思是这说明了她可以自行恢复
Wait. Lissa does something like that to herself?
等等 莉萨身上也发生过这种事吗？
- Cuts and scars and... - Yes.
- 伤口 伤疤以及 - 是的
Christian,she really could have used your support these past few weeks.
克里斯琴 在这过去的几周里 她本该接受你的支持的
You agreed Lissa hasn't been herself.
你也说过莉萨不是真正的她了
It's her fault we're not together.
我们没有在一起是她的问题
God,the female,especially one who lives off of blood and magic,
天啊 对于一个女性来说 特别是一个靠鲜血和魔法为生的女性
is going to have her mood swings.
情绪波动通常都是很大的
It is never the girl's fault,even when it is the girl's fault.
错永远不在女孩子 即使真的是女孩子错了
No one ever explained that to you?
之前都没人跟你讲过吗？
You know,if you weren't so psychotic,you'd be fun to hang outwith.
你知道吗 如果你不是这么神经质你应该是一个不错的伙伴
Same to you,creep.
你也一样 怪胎
Thank you.
谢谢
OK,bye.
好 拜
- OK. - See ya.
- 再见 - 再见
What were you doing with Rose? You were fornicating,weren't you?
你跟萝丝在一起做什么？你们有一腿？
Fornicat... We were reading.
不是 我们是在找资料
We discovered a magic called Spirit. You have it.
我们发现了一种叫灵魂的魔法 你拥有这种魔法
Ms. Karp had it,and so did St. Vladimir.
卡普女士有 圣弗拉迪米尔也有
- He used to cut himself,too. - Rose told you that?
- 他也切伤过自己 - 是萝丝告诉你的吗？
- I'm gonna kill her. - Look,stop it,Lissa.
- 我要杀了她 - 听着 别这样 莉萨
We're trying to help you.
我们是想帮你
I know now if you don't have any family,
我知道如今你没有任何家人
you need as many friends as you possibly...
你需要尽可能多的朋友
I don't need friends or family or pets or...
我不需要朋友 家人或者宠物或者
I hate you!
我恨你
You liar.
骗子
- Lissa,listen... - Don't "Lissa,listen" me.
- 莉萨 听我说 - 去你的"听我说"
- You've ruined my life. - Oh,bite me.
- 你毁了我的生活 - 来 要我呀
- You wish,blood whore. - Wow.
- 你想得美 贱人 - 哇哦
OK,Lissa,I need you to understand.
好吧 莉萨我需要你的理解
We can learn how St. Vladimir used Spirit...
我们可以了解圣弗拉迪米尔 是怎么用意念精神
- Did you kill my cat? - Hey,
- 是你杀了我的猫吗？- 嘿
Oscar and I's relationship was on the mend.
奥斯卡和我的关系那时已经在不断改进了
Lissa,this is important. Ms. Karp turned herself Strigoi.
莉萨这很重要 卡普女士把自己变成了血族
She didn't do it to become evil. She did it to take away from...
她这么做不是为了让自己变邪恶 她是为了摆脱
the scratching and the shaking. I mean...
不由自主的抓伤和颤抖 我是想说
which future do you want,a sick and soulless one like Karp's
将来你想成为哪一种 想卡普一样恶心而且没有灵魂
or an epic one like Vladimir's?
还是像弗拉迪米尔一样伟大
Stop talking to me about the past and the future,
不要跟我谈过去和将来
because I only care about the present.
因为我只关心现在
You know,if you have to choose one,pick the one that's happening right now.
要知道 如果你必须要选择的话 那就选择一个正在发生的吧
I am Princess Vasilisa Dragomir.
我是公主瓦西里萨·德拉古米尔
I'm the last of the Dragomir line.
我是德拉古米尔一脉的最后一员
If they see I'm weak,they'll attack.
如果他们看到我软弱 他们就会攻击
This isn't about a "they" anymore. This is about you! This is...
这跟"他们"没有关系 这是关于你自己 这是
You're awake,finally.
你终于醒了
The princess has been going through feeders all morning.
公主一整个早上都在充当供给者
How are you?
你怎么样了？
I don't know. You tell me.
我不知道 你觉得呢？
I'm afraid to even look.
我都不敢看自己
I can move it,that's a good sign,right?
我还能动 这是个好现象 对吗？
Rose,I don't know how to say this,but...
萝丝 我不知道要怎么跟你说但是
you are not injured.
你并没有受伤
That's easy for you to say,comrade.
你说的轻松 老兄
I heard the crack. I saw the bone...
我当时都听到骨头断裂的声音了 我看到骨头
Sorry to interrupt.
不好意思打扰一下
- Hey. - Hi.
- 嘿 - 嗨
- Here. - Thanks.
- 给 - 谢谢
So,I saw Aaron go by.
我刚看到阿伦经过了
- I kicked him to the curb. - Mmm.
- 我把他踢了 - 嗯
When I saw your leg,I got everything out of my system.
当我看到你的腿时 我对所有事情的态度都改变了
- Everything. - Thanks for that,by the way.
- 所有事情 - 谢谢
Ugh.
嗯哼
I'm so glad you're both alive and not at each other's throats.
很高兴看到你们俩都活着 而没互掐脖子
This whole matter of Spirit has taken us by surprise.
灵魂魔法的事情让大家非常吃惊
Until the advisers arrive from Romania,
在来自罗马尼亚的顾问没到来之前
we'll be sequestering you both into a bunker,
我们会把你们俩都禁闭起来
away from any excitement.
不准参加娱乐活动
No classes,and obviously you will not be attending
不准上课 当然很明显你也不能参加
- the Equinox Dance tonight. - Oh,nonsense.
- 今晚的舞会 - 噢 胡说
Please,you have to come.
你一定得去
I'm gonna go with the headmistress on this one,Prince Dashkov.
在这一点上我支持校长 达什科夫王子
Besides,we're all forgetting the most important thing.
除此之外 我们都忘了最重要的一件事了
- We have nothing to wear. - There the gods have smiled upon us.
- 我们没有参加舞会的衣服 - 上帝眷顾了我们
Today is an overcast day,
今天天气不错
and I have engineered a little shopping expedition.
我组织了一个小型的购物"远征"
Please? You know how much I need your help.
拜托了 你知道我都多么需要你的帮助
And plus,when has shopping ever not cheered you up,Lissa?
再说了 购物通常都是让你很兴奋的莉萨
Where is Rose?
萝丝去哪儿了？
OK.
好吧
What was that about?
那是干什么？
It's just a little something Dimitri and I do to keep each other on our toes.
就是一些让我和迪米特里时刻保持警惕的事
Wow,that was weak. How long have you been in crush with him?
哇哦 那也太弱了吧 你和他训练多久了
I am... very sure that I don't know what you're talking about.
我 很确定我不知道你在说什么
- So,do I get a silver stake? - That would be a... no.
- 所以 我能拿一个银锥吗？- 当然 不可以
But remember,today you are not just Lissa's friend.
但是记住 今天你不仅仅是莉萨的朋友
Spiridon.
斯皮里敦
Ain't likely any Strigoi is gonna make a play
不会有血族的人
in a public place in broad daylight,
大白天的在公共场合闹事的
but if Dimitri ain't giving you a stake,missy,
但是如果迪米特里 不打算给你一个小银桩
you should have one of these bad boys.
至少你还有我们
'Causes a blinding flash of UV light. Buy you some time.
亮瞎狗眼的紫外线手电 会给你赢得一些时间
Well,at least someone thinks I'm worth a weapon.
起码还是有人觉得 我值得拥有一件武器
So,my superpower turned out to also be my Kryptonite.
所以 我的超能力其实也是我的氪星石
Wow,Your Highness with the pop culture reference.
哇 殿下还聊到了流行文化里的超人了
You know,I...
你知道 我
I confused power with popularity.
我把力量和受欢迎程度混为一谈
Ever wonder what it'd be like to be like that?
我曾想过如果像她们那样的话会怎样
It's not our destiny.
我们的命运不会是那样的
Destiny? I hate that word.
命运？我讨厌这个词
You know,"royal responsibility,"
要知道"王室的责任感"
"the Moroi come first," it's all so twisted.
"莫里族优先" 太扭曲了
It's not twisted.
没有扭曲
I'm your Dhampir and you're my Moroi. Done.
我就是你的拜尔族守护者 你就是我的莫里族 就这样
Some days we're kooky teenagers,
有时候我们是奇怪的青少年
and other days I'm risking my neck to protect you
但有时候我又冒死保护你
from an ancient race of predatory vampires...
不受一个古老的吸血鬼种族的伤害
or whoever else,and that's life.
或者说是其他什么 这就是人生
At least until they come up with a better word for it.
直到他们想到一个更好的词来形容
Somebody looks tense. Free massage?
有人看上去很紧张 要免费按摩吗？
I'm really sorry. I'm so sorry,OK?
真的非常抱歉 很抱歉
Run.
快走
Ms. Karp,I understand all that,but Mia and my brother...
卡普女士 我能理解 但是米娅和我的哥哥
don't think so.
不这样认为
Andre was generous and funny and amazing,
安德烈是很慷慨 有趣而且很棒
but... he could kind of be a player.
但是 他可能是只是玩玩儿
Lissa,don't look like you don't know what I'm talking about,
莉萨 不要表现得好像听不懂我在说什么一样
'cause I can feel you,OK?
别忘了我能感应到你 好吗？
You know,I hate having a best friend I can't lie to.
你知道吗 我很讨厌拥有一个不能对其撒谎的好朋友
Do you really think Mini-Mia's behind everything?
你真的认为小米娅是幕后者吗？
No,not exactly.
不 不完全这样
But I think we'll find out tonight.
但是我想我们今晚就能确定了
Tomorrow you're getting sequestered away by Spirit advisers,
明天你就要因为灵魂魔法被关禁闭了
so the dance is the last chance for anybody to try to get to you.
所以今晚的舞会对于想要接近你的人来说是最后一次机会
Look,if you could put a pin in all that,we have more vital matters.
好吧 你能否把这些暂且放一边 我们还有更重要的事情
Finding you a dress.
给自己挑一条裙子吧
I can go into my trust fund.
我可以给你买单
I could not possibly accept that.
我可能不会接受
That's your dress. That's the dress you were born to wear.
那条裙子适合你 那简直就是为你打造的
Lissa,we have more important things to do than sh...
莉萨 我们还有很多重要的事情要做
That is my dress.
那是我的裙子
Thank you,sir,and if you could just sign here?
谢谢您 先生 可以麻烦您在这边签个字吗？
And that is your necklace.
这条项链适合你
That is my necklace.
这是我的项链
That's not your necklace.
这条项链不属于你
So not my necklace.
好吧 那就不是咯
Did you take my lip gloss?
你拿了我的润唇膏吗？
Corpse Number Five? Like I'd wear your pale-ass lip gloss.
五号尸体色吗？我倒是希望能用一下你的惨白的润唇膏
No way.
没门儿
Natalie,you look gorgeous.
娜塔莉 你看起来好漂亮啊
Rose... this is for you,from my father.
萝丝 这是我爸爸送给你的
That's my necklace.
这是我的项链
Daddy saw you looking at it. Here.
老爹注意到你盯着它 拿着
谢谢你为公主和我的娜塔莉做的一切 有你这样的守护天使 她们真幸运 维克多
- How does it look? - Beautiful.
- 看起来怎样 - 漂亮极了
这事最后一次跳舞
All right,ladies.
注意了 姑娘们
I don't know what's gonna happen tonight.
我不知道今晚会发生什么
At this point,I can't remember who loves us and who hates us...
这会儿 我没法记住谁是朋友谁是敌人
but I do know that we are going to own this dance.
但我清楚 我们要在舞会狂欢
Let's make tonight our bitch.
今晚爽个够吧
Not much of a reaction from your boyfriend.
你男朋友貌似反应不大
He's not my boyfriend,but... grading on the Dimitri curve,
那才不是我男朋友 不过 以迪米特里为标准来看
a huge reaction... mammoth,gargantuan.
刚刚也算很大的反应了 相当大 超级大
Come here.
来
Genuinely un-small.
反正不算小
Christian Ozera.
克里斯琴·奥泽拉
At a school dance.
没想到在学校的舞会遇到
After this week,I thought I'd lost the ability to be surprised.
上周过后 我还以为我不会再有惊喜了
I'm sorry about that kiss the other day.
关于那天的吻 我说句抱歉
What about the one right now?
那 现在这个呢
- Rose. - Hey,what's up?
- 萝丝 - 嘿 怎么了
- OK. - Rose,you look...
- 好吧 - 萝丝 你看起来
No,you don't get to stare at her.
不不不 谁让你看她了
I took it upon myself to talk to these royal pains in the butt.
我亲自跟这俩个 净给皇家添乱的小混蛋谈了谈
Hmm.
嗯
Don't you have something to say?
你们有什么要说的
- We're sorry. - Hmm.
- 我们很抱歉 - 哼
We didn't do anything to you that we said we did.
我们说要对 你做的那些事其实都没做
You're telling something that never happened actually never happened?
你是在说那些本来就没发生的事其实本来就没发生么
Thanks.
哟 那谢谢
Mia let us have sex with her if we obeyed her.
如果我们服从米娅的命令 她就准我们和她上床
I tagged the note at the church and air-blasted the memorial.
是我在教堂贴的便笺 也是我在教堂打碎了她父母的纪念碑
What did you think of the scary screen saver?
那个恐怖的屏保你们觉得怎么样？
We actually put a lot of work into that.
我们为那个花了好些心思呢
And the bloody one just happened.
还有刚刚在墙上写的血字
We thought it'd be fun to all hook up in the princess's room,
我们觉得在公主的房间里 干点坏事会很好玩
and things got out of hand,literally.
没想到事情搞砸了 额
It's called blood splash. It's a new Moroi fad,
那叫血绘 是莫里族的新时尚
where when things get hot and sticky,you fang open your wrist and spray.
就是当事情变得棘手的时候 就咬开手腕画画玩
Ew! Stop. I nap on that couch.
恶心 别说了 我常在下面那个沙发上打盹的好不好
OK,what about the cat?
那 猫的事儿呢？
We thought it was a fox.
我们以为那是只狐狸
Hurting animals... that's disgusting.
伤害小动物 是蛮恶心的
Said the creepy blood splasher.
呵呵 刚刚承认在别人墙上洒血的变态也会这么想啊
Please,Rose,don't kick my ass.
求你了 萝丝 别这么戳我
Go dance with Natalie.
跟娜塔莉跳舞去
Go,now.
去啊 快
Oh,Jesse.
唉 杰西
- Who's the man? - You are so the man.
- 所以你的舞伴是？- 反正不是你
Break the case wide open and I still only get the cheek.
哥为打开局面做了这么多 竟然只在脸上得到一个吻
Ouch.
真忧伤
Ever feel like you're being watched?
有没有觉得过你被注视着？
Can we pretend the past month never happened?
这个月的事儿能先别提么
Why were you in the hospital? Pregnant?
你去医院干嘛？怀孕了么？
- I guess not. - Herpes?
- 我猜不是的 - 得疱疹了？
Maybe your baby has herpes. I don't care if it's true. I'll tell...
估计你的小宝宝得疱疹了吧 不管是不是真的 我都会告诉
- Go away,Mia. - Why are you Dragomirs such drags?
- 走开 米娅 - 你们这些拜尔人怎么这么讨嫌？
First Andre,then you steal Aaron from me and don't even keep him.
先是抢走安德烈 然后又是阿伦 还一点都不珍惜他
- I don't need this. - I vow to take down the entire...
- 你看着办 - 我要把你们所有拜尔人都
I'll fire-magic you into ash.
再逼逼信不信哥用火魔法烧了你
I'll just water-magic myself before you can...
那我先用水魔法把
Gosh,you two are a riot. Allow me,Mr. Ozera.
我的天 你们俩啊 让我来吧 奥泽拉先生
Rose,I hear you and the princess are friends again.
萝丝 我听说你跟公主又混一起了
Too bad... could have made a great team.
真可惜 找了那种猪队友
Oh,nice wrist corsage,Splashy.
腕带很可爱啊 沾了不少血吧
Your sex slaves told me everything,and poor Aaron
你的小性奴们都跟我坦白了 而可怜的阿伦
had no idea what a sociopath you really are.
你这么反社会 阿伦他造吗
- I'll bet you did off Lissa's cat. - Oscar? I gave him treats.
- 我敢肯定莉萨的猫是你弄死的 - 奥斯卡吗？我对它很好的
I would never hurt a kitty.
我才不会伤害小猫咪呢
Oh,my God,you poor little...
我的天 你这弱
All this time,me thinking that you're a villain
这么久以来 我还以为你是大坏蛋
when you're really just...
没想到你只是
you're just an insecure little girl in desperate need of attention.
你只是个因为没有安全感才瞎捣乱的小屁孩
Everyone saw that I tried to take the high road there.
你们都看到 我本来想君子动口不动手的
- Rose. - Sort of.
- 萝丝 - 至少我是那么想的
If Mia didn't do it,that means there's a bigger threat still out there.
如果都不是米娅干的 那么一定有更大的危险还潜伏在身边
- Hathaway,you're out of here. - Lissa's run off. I didn't see where.
- 海瑟薇 你给我出去 - 莉萨跑掉了 我不知道她去哪儿了
Oh,God,if only there was a secret place that she went to when she was sad.
我的天呐 要是她难过的时候会去一个秘密的地方就好了
- Right. - Genius.
- 对啊 - 我是个天才
OK,OK.
淡定 淡定
OK.
淡定
Please,please,please,please.
快点快点 让我看看你
- Christian. - We need to get you somewhere safe.
- 克里斯琴 - 我们得把你弄到一个安全的地方
- Just a little longer in the moonlight. - No,no.
- 我只想在月光下多呆一小会 - 不行不行
Our moonlight.
属于我们的月光
OK,now we need to go.
好了 该撤了
Lissa.
莉萨
Headmistress Kirova,we need to get Dimitri.
基洛娃校长 我们得赶紧找到迪米特里
- The princess is in trouble. - She's not the only one.
- 公主有大麻烦了 - 有麻烦的可不止她一个哦
- You don't understand. - I do understand,Rose.
- 你不懂事情有多严重 - 我当然懂
I understand more than you'll ever...
我比你要清楚得多
I could have been a model.
我本来可以当模特的
A man in Milan gave me his card when I was 16.
我16岁在米兰的时候 有个男人给了我一张名片
Dimitri? Dimitri,open up.
迪米特里？迪米特里快开门
Dimitri,something has happened.
迪米特里 出事儿了
Rose,what's wrong?
萝丝 出什么事儿了？
What's right?
出大事儿了
Sweet sassy molassey.
这身材简直棒呆
What do you want,Rose?
你想干嘛 萝丝？
Some of that.
你觉得呢
This is insane.
这太疯狂了
What are we doing?
我们在干嘛？
Everything.
想干嘛就干嘛
I love your dress.
我喜欢你这裙子
Let's burn it.
烧了它吧
Love charms... hypnotic,dangerous,put over jewelry...
情欲咒 能催眠 很危险 被施放在珠宝上
Forget about it. Lissa's been kidnapped. We have to hurry.
别管它了 莉萨被绑架了 抓紧时间
Report from the gate. Nothing's come in or out.
大门报告 没有人员出入
They're still on academy ground... Have you cleared this with Kirova?
他们都在学院里 你跟基洛娃解释过了么？
Better to beg forgiveness than ask permission.
还是先斩后奏来得方便
Yeah,and I put a sedative in her ass.
没错 而且我还在她屁股上打了针镇静剂
Let me concentrate. You've got to be kidding me.
我得集中精力想想 你在逗我呢
- What is it? - Nothing. Hold on. OK.
- 怎么了？- 没什么 没事儿 尽管开车
He's coming in.
他来了
Check the blindfold. No compulsion tonight.
检查下绷带遮严没 今晚谁都别被施上强迫术了
I can't make out anything through the blindfold,
绷带遮得严严实实 我什么都看不见
but I know that voice. It's... that guardian.
不过我认得那声音 是 是那个守护者的
- Oh,no. - "Oh,no," what?
- 噢 别这样 - 恩？怎么了？
"Oh,no," who. The bad guy's Victor Dashkov.
那个人 那坏家伙是维克多·达什科夫
Welcome,Vasilisa.
欢迎啊 公主殿下
How was the dance?
舞会怎么样？
It's officially tomorrow,and,as promised,
实际上是定在明天 然后 按照计划
we have much to talk about.
我们有很多要谈的事情
Forgive me if I don't make eye contact.
请原谅我不与您做眼神交流
- I've seen you in action. - Why are you doing this?
- 我是见识过你的强迫术的 - 你为什么这么做？
My dear,the simple truth is,I need you to heal me.
亲爱的 事实很简单 我需要你治好我
Testing you with the animals was misguided,
用动物来试验你是失策
but earth-magicking the cement and shattering Rose's ankle
但是水泥地上弄折萝丝的脚踝那次
was supremely clarifying.
就非常明确了
You're forgetting something.
你忘记了重要的事情
My bond with Rose is practically a psychic GPS.
我和萝丝的联结就像GPS一样
Ah,yes,but the necklace gift that I gave to Rose
啊 没错 但是我送给萝丝作礼物的项链
is bathed in a very expensive love charm,
可是施放了很强力的情欲咒的
and she is a little too preoccupied to be of much use to you.
而且 她被你利用得太投入了
That's what you think,mother... Victor wants her to heal him.
竟然是这么想的 你这混蛋 维克多想要她治好他
You were my family's most cherished friend.
你曾经是我们家族最珍视的朋友
Why didn't you just ask me?
为什么不直接开口让我帮忙呢？
How touching... genuinely,my darling,
多么感人 真的 亲爱的公主
but a chronic disease like my Sandovsky's needs
但是 像我们家族的这种慢性病
continual healings,and then there is the other matter.
需要长期的治疗 于是会有这么个问题
The physical toll on me.
我会受到伤害
Yes,Spirit users take their power from their own essence.
没错 运用灵魂魔法的人从自身得到力量
To heal another requires giving part of oneself,
要治疗别人的话 需要他牺牲自己的一部分
and it can destroy one over time.
这久而久之会毁掉一个人
You want me to give up my life for yours.
为了治好你自己 你愿意让我死
Basically. But,you see,my dear,
基本上是这样 不过 你得明白
I am much more important than you,
我比你重要得多
and the Moroi need a strong leader,but my disease means
莫里族需要一个强大的领袖 而我的病意味着
that I cannot occupy my rightful place upon the throne.
我没法行使我登上王座的合法权利
But you shouldn't bother your pretty little head
不过 你这可爱的小脑袋
about all this royal intrigue.
没必要费力弄清这场皇室的密谋
Guess what,Victor.
听好了 维克多
The spirit in this pretty little head isn't going to heal you.
我这可爱的小脑袋不会用它的魔力来治疗你
- You can't make me. - Bring in Kenneth.
- 你没法强迫我的 - 让肯尼斯进来
Do you know somebody named Kenneth?
你认识一个叫肯尼斯的家伙吗？
Your compulsion won't work on Kenneth.
你的强迫术拿他没辙的
He's blind,but he's one of the Moroi's most ingenious air users.
他没有视力 但他对空气魔法的掌控炉火纯青
- Shall we begin? Heal me. - Go to hell.
- 开始吧 治好我 - 去死
You're up,Kenneth.
肯尼斯 靠你了
Rose?
萝丝？
Don't stop. They're torturing her.
继续开车 他们在折磨她
Heal me.
治不治
Now he's...
现在他在
Ah,Lissa.
啊 莉萨
Heal me.
快点
My...
我的天
this really worked out.
这真的有用
Take the girl upstairs till departure.
把这姑娘带到楼上
Rose,stay here. It's too dangerous,you'll just get in the way.
萝丝 呆在这儿 太危险了 你会拖后腿的
- But... - Do I really need to remind you
- 可是 - 非要我提醒你
the last time I said "stay in the car"
上次我说呆在车里被当耳边风
and was disobeyed?
结果发生了什么吗？
No,I totally understand. Good luck.
好吧 我完全了解 注意安全
- You're not really staying,are you? - What do you think?
- 你不会真的乖乖留这儿吧？- 你说呢？
But what did Dimitri mean by "last time I said 'stay in the car" ?
可是 迪米特里说上次呆在车里 那是什么事儿？
He was talking about another girl from another time.
他说的是另一个姑娘
She was a novice.
那是个菜鸟
I'm a guardian.
姐是个正式的守护者
Let's roll,fire magic. I need a seeing-eye dog.
咱们上 玩火的魔法师 我需要个好搭档
Take my arm. The princess is upstairs.
扶我的胳膊吧 公主在楼上
No,no,not this way.
不不不 是另一边
- Rose. - Keep going.
- 萝丝 - 别停下来
- It's right up there. - Rose!
- 就在上面了 - 萝丝
What?!
啥？
Spiridon,send for the girl.
斯皮里敦 把那姑娘带下来
We're ready now.
我们就位了
I believe you can fly.
我觉得你会飞哦
Feel free to chime in at any time with some fire magic.
什么时候想用火魔法 你随意哈
Maybe a ring of flame around the knob?
要不帅哥你现在帮我把门把手烧掉？
I've never really worked outside a classroom setting before.
其实我从没在教室外面试过的
Forget it,she's gone.
啊 不用了 她逃脱了
Stop trying to save yourself,Liss.
别乱跑了 莉萨
Stupid one-way bond.
这愚蠢的单向联结
Psi-hounds.
恶灵犬
Expensive to breed,difficult to train,
养起来烧钱 驯起来费力
but there is no denying the brilliance of the psi-hounds.
但它们的天才用处绝对值得
They will stalk the princess,maneuver her,
它们会跟踪她 把她逼到合适的地方
but they won't attack unless I say the word.
但是直到我下令 它们才会攻击
I presume you can deal with that?
我说 你是不是该搞定他们？
They say Dimitri is a god.
听说迪米特里就是战神
Well,I'm an atheist... an atheist with a big gun.
不过我是个无神论者 一个有枪的无神论者
That's it? Seriously?
这么萎？你在逗我吧？
I've waited for this moment.
这一刻我等了好久
Do you know what it's like to always be referred to as the second best guardian?
你知道在守护者中只能当千年老二有多憋屈吗？
No.
反正我没当过
Are you OK?
没事儿吧？
- Did you see what Victor did? - I know. What an asshole.
- 你看到维克多都干了些什么吧？- 嗯 他真是个人渣
I hate to interrupt,but unless either of you can fly a chopper,
我确实不想打扰你们 不过 有人会开直升机吗
maybe we should get going.
没有的话咱得赶紧撤啊
Lissa,get back.
莉萨 退后
Rose,be a dear and step away from the princess.
萝丝 听话 离公主远一点
I don't want to accidentally shoot her when I'm shooting you.
我可不想在瞄准你的时候不小心射到她
You heard him,he won't shoot me.
他说了 他不会朝我开枪的
- I am your guardian. - No,Rose,you can't do this.
- 我才是守护者有没有搞错啊 - 不 萝丝 听我的
Lissa,don't you dare fight. Lissa.
莉萨 你别跟我倔 莉萨
- You're worse than a Strigoi. - Christian!
- 你比血族还渣 - 克里斯琴
Do you know what I like most about the psi-hounds?
你知道恶灵犬最赞的是什么吗？
They're wonderful at tracking. They're even better at killing.
它们追踪的本领已经够强了 但是说到杀戮
Attack!
上
No.
不要啊
Now,that's some freaking fire magic.
哇哦 刚刚的火魔法太亮了
Rose,I need to save him,but I can't.
萝丝 我得救他 可是现在不行
Victor took everything,all my energy.
维克多把我的能量都夺走了
Power up,Princess.
公主 来冲个电吧
This has been a night that St. Vladimir's will never forget.
圣弗拉米尔学院会永远铭记今晚
We have extra guardians manning the academy perimeter. Nothing can get in.
我们安排了守护者在学院周边警戒 没什么东西能进来
Victor Dashkov will be confined to a holding cell downstairs
维克多·达什科夫将被关押在地下监狱
until he can be transferred to the Royal Court Prison to await trial.
不久会被押送到皇家法院监狱等待审判
How's Natalie? She worshipped her father. She must be devastated.
娜塔莉怎么样了？她多崇拜自己的父亲 她肯定难受疯了
The other members of the Dashkov family are removing her from school.
达什科夫家的其他人正在想办法让她退学
For the best.
这样最好
Uh-oh,Rose. This came for you.
哦 萝丝 这个是给你的
Oh,great.
哦 很好
Uh,Dimitri,one last thing...
还有 迪米特里 最后一件事
The time gap after Rose so dramatically burst out of my office...
萝丝神奇地从我办公室跑出去后的这段时间
It should all be explained in the other file.
别的文件里会解释的
A Nobu charm was put on a necklace Rose had been wearing.
萝丝戴着的项链上被施了决斗咒
The spell caused Rose to attack me and me to attack her.
那当时让我们俩互相攻击了一阵
I disengaged the necklace before critical... violence could occur.
在发生严重的后果前 我把项链拽下来了
Mmm.
嗯哼
Hey,we should probably talk about what happened earlier.
嘿 刚刚你编的那些 我们该谈谈吧
I just want you to know I would never use the words
我只是想让你明白 要不是受了项链的影响
"sweet sassy molassey" unless under the influence.
我才不会说你的身材什么的呢
It is not a matter of amusement or discussion.
这事儿一点都不好玩 咱也别提了
- It was horrific. - Horrific...
- 那太惊悚了 - 惊悚
isn't really the first adjective that comes to mind.
不可能是脑子里蹦出来的第一个词吧
Don't make light of this.
别想多了
It's one thing if I were 36 and you were 28,
如果我36 你28
or me 28 and you 20.
或者我28岁 你20岁是不一样的
That's a lot of math for someone who's not interested.
对一个想略过这事儿的人来说 这算数还算是花了点心思的
Your life is about homework,dances,parties.
你的生活是作业 舞会和聚会
How can you say that after what happened?
这几天刚发生的这些事儿你瞎了吗？
It's what it should be about.
但那是你本该有的生活
I'm not interested in you in that way.
而我对那并不感兴趣
- OK. - It was...
- 好吧 - 那只是
just a spell.
只是个咒语而已
- Let it go. - Got it.
- 忘了它吧 - 好的
- Rose? - Yeah?
- 萝丝？- 怎么了？
You're still here?
你还在这儿？
I'm not sure how I feel about this,
尽管这让我感觉很奇怪
but Victor has requested a moment of your time.
但我还是得告诉你 维克多想跟你单独谈谈
Yeah,no,that's not gonna happen.
好吧 哦不 我是说 没门儿
He said something about you being "shadow-kissed"?
他说了些关于你是"影吻的"？
She's not going. That's final.
她不会去的 不用多说了
Don't tell me what to do.
不用你来说话
You look good,Vic.
气色不错啊 维克
Which is ironic,considering it means more time rotting in jail.
讽刺的是 这意味着你得好好享受在监狱慢慢烂掉的感觉
Don't take this the wrong way,Rose,but...
别理解错我的意思 萝丝 不过
I probably should have killed you.
我觉得我早该杀了你
There's a compliment in there somewhere.
这还算句奉承话呢
I spent a lot of money on that charm.
我在那个咒语上花了不少钱
It didn't quite work out the way I wanted.
可是看来效果不太好啊
Mmm. It worked out well enough.
嗯 我倒觉得效果挺好
Caused a man with no interest in me to burn off my dress,so...
竟然能让一个对我毫无兴趣的男人烧掉我的裙子 所以
You're so tough,so one-of-a-kind.
你很有个性 够犟
But you're still a girl. All this has happened,
不过你毕竟是个小女生 所有这些事情之后
and what you want to know is,"Does Dimitri really like me?"
你一心想知道的事情就是 "迪米特里真的喜欢我吗？"
It's a powerful charm,Rose,but it's not that powerful.
那个咒语确实很强力 萝丝 但没有那么强
There has to be a degree of affection and attraction already in place.
它发挥作用前提的是 你们俩本来就有一定程度的爱护吸引
Happy?
开心了？
- Shadow-kissed? - Ah,yes. I owe you that.
- 影吻的？- 啊 对 这事儿我还要跟你讲
You see,I didn't begin to track Vasilisa
我对莉萨的追踪并不是
with some silly old raven.
以老套的蠢乌鸦开始的
My eye was on her long before.
我老早就盯上她了
I've seen the accident report.
我看过车祸的事故报告
And there's absolutely no way that either of you should have survived.
你们俩绝对不应该能活下来的
The accident was what woke her spirit in the first place.
但那次车祸第一次唤醒了她的灵魂魔法
The fear of seeing you dead made it burst out,
她害怕你死去 所以能量爆发了
allowing her to heal,made you form your bond.
让她能治愈你 而且建立了你们的联结
Rose...
萝丝
you've been kissed by shadows.
你得到过阴影的亲吻
You've crossed over into death,
你曾进入过死亡的世界
into the other side,and returned.
到了另一边 然后回来了
Don't you think that leaves a mark on the soul... somewhere?
难道你不觉得那会在灵魂某处留下一个 印记吗？
That's why you're not afraid to show your feelings,Rose,
那就是你不怕表现出自己情绪的原因 萝丝
your passion,your anger.
你的激情 你的愤怒
That's what makes you remarkable. Yes.
那让你引人瞩目 没错
But it's ironic... considering.
不过讽刺的是 因此
Considering what?
什么？
Considering I'll have to kill you.
因此我得杀了你
Natalie. You made your own daughter turn Strigoi?
娜塔莉 你把自己的亲生女儿变成了血族？
And how do you think I can circumvent the outside security?
不然你觉得我是怎么绕过外面的防御的？
I'd do anything for my daddy.
为了我爹我可是什么都愿意做的
All that training,and yet,I'm going to obliterate you.
你训练得那么努力 不过 我还是会捏死你
You see,Natalie was not the innocent you thought she was.
你也看到了 娜塔莉并不是你以为的小绵羊
In fact,she was the one who provided me with the intel
实际上 正是她帮我出得主意
regarding you,Dimitri and Vasilisa.
来对付你 迪米特里和莉萨
The cat was my idea.
猫咪的事儿是我干的
Daddy wanted to do another fox.
我爹本来是想用另一只狐狸了事的
Father,look.
爸 你看
Rose does choke before Strigoi.
萝丝在血族面前还是会喘粗气的
I don't understand.
我不懂
To become a Strigoi,don't you have to...
要变成血族 你不是要
Yes. I chose Ray to be my first.
没错 雷是第一个
Killing him was a lot more fun
杀他有意思多了
than losing my virginity to him would've been.
相比之下 当时想把贞洁给他的念头真是无聊透顶
And with a lot more blood
流的血也多得多是吧
Too soon?
这么经不起诱惑？
Hey,Victor?
嘿 维克多？
Aren't you afraid your new Strigoi daughter
你不担心你现在是血族的宝贝女儿
won't be able to resist your Moroi veins?
会觉得你的血液也难以抗拒吗？
Don't be ludicrous.
别搞笑了
I'm gonna wait outside,Natalie.
我在外面等你 娜塔莉
Finish her off.
快点解决她
You don't know what high school is like for a loser like me.
你无法理解 高中对我这样失败者是怎样的折磨
I was so scared all the time...
我总是害怕
so weak,so sad,so lame.
又弱又伤心 还蹩脚
Now my eyesight is perfect,
现在我有完美的视力
my skin is clear,and so is my mind.
白皙的皮肤 还有转得飞快的大脑
I may be dead,but I have never felt so alive.
也许我已经死了 但我从没有像现在这样生气勃勃
How awesome for you. Say cheese.
你是厉害啊 说茄子
Rose?
萝丝？
Oh.
哦
Maybe I won't kill you.
也许我不会杀你
Maybe I'll make you just like me.
要不我就把你变成同类吧
That way,we can be friends forever and ever.
那样我们就永远永远是好朋友咯
BFF!
好闺蜜哦
Who's choking now?
呐 现在是谁在喘气了？
Roza,Roza.
萝丝 萝丝
Oh,my Roza.
哦 我的萝丝
Lissa,you're gonna want to see this.
莉萨 你一定想看看这个的
I don't believe my eyes. You got him wearing a color other than black.
不可思议 你竟然能让他开始穿黑色以外的衣服了
Baby steps.
小意思
Oh,Rose,wait.
哦 萝丝 来
There's so much to read here.
这里有好多故事
Apparently,Vladimir and Anna almost drowned in this flood,
显而易见 弗拉迪米尔和安娜差点在洪水里淹死
but he saved them from certain death,and listen to this.
但是他硬是把他俩从鬼门关拉了回来 呐 是这样的
"It took many years for Vladimir to master the power of his Spirit."
"弗拉迪米尔花了很多年来掌控自己灵魂的力量"
"Despite his sufferings and delusions,"
"他尽管承受了无尽的折磨和幻觉"
"he never contemplated the way of the Strigoi,"
"都没有选择索性变成一个血族"
"because he always had the strength"
"因为他的安娜"
"of his shadow-kissed guardian,Anna,to see him through."
"他那影吻的守护者 安娜的坚守一直支持着他"
Similarities. Weird.
真巧 有意思
Well,Christian,for us,weird...
其实 克里斯琴 对我们而言 有意思
Doesn't begin to cover it.
远远不止有意思
Do I have to?
非得这样嘛？
It's time.
是时候了
God,not her. Not now.
我的天 又是她 真是会选时间
And once again,this grotesque maelstrom of indecency
看来 这种怪异的轮回
seems centered on one royal individual.
又一次聚焦到了一个皇室成员身上
- Where's Vasilisa Drag... - Thank you,Your Majesty,
- 莉萨在哪儿 - 谢谢您 女王大人
for allowing me to clear the air.
让我来说吧
I finally declared a magic,and it's called Spirit.
我总算学到了一种魔法 灵魂之术
It may take years to get a handle on it,
也许我得花好些年才能掌握它
but I have a bunch of wise men in robes to help me out.
但我一直都会有一帮智慧的朋友帮助我
And yes,that was not a mirage you saw on the dance floor.
没错 你们之前在舞会上看到的并不是幻觉
My boyfriend is Christian Ozera,and his parents were Strigoi.
我的男朋友是克里斯琴·奥泽拉 他的父母是血族
Get over it. He has.
不骗你们 但这没什么大不了
I'm not quite sure what you think...
我不知道你在想什么
Shh! Not now,dear.
嘘 亲爱的 先听我说
Blood. Blood is what connects us all.
血液 血液是连接我们所有人关系的东西
Blood is sustenance.
血液是维系
Blood is family.
血液是家庭
Blood is pain,and blood is death,
血液是痛苦 也是死亡
be it the fang of the Strigoi
它可以是血族的利牙
or a drunk driver on the wrong side of the road.
也可以是醉酒逆行的司机
Blood is many things,
血液可以是很多东西
and sometimes it gets so crazy and confusing
有时候世界变得疯狂 让你迷茫
that you need a best friend to tell you,"it's OK."
你需要一位挚友来告诉你 "一切都会好的"
"It's all life,at least until they come up with a better word for it."
"这就是生活 随便你们怎么称它"
Unfortunately,you can't all have a Rose Hathaway.
很不幸 不是每一个人都有像萝丝·海瑟薇这样的挚友
I'm very lucky that she's mine,
拥有她我真是太幸运了
but if you don't have a soul mate,by Vlad,the least you deserve
但是 即使你并不拥有一个灵魂伴侣 至少你也值得
is kindness and dignity and something more original than gossip,
被温柔和尊重地对待 而不是受到谣言
snobbiness,slut-shaming and bullying.
势利 羞辱和欺凌的困扰
Let's prove that Moroi blood is worth protecting.
让我们证明 莫里族的血液值得被保护
What do you say,everyone?
各位 你们说呢？
No more bad blood.
不要再有邪恶的血液了
So,that's Natalie,huh?
那是杀娜塔莉留下的印记？
Looks... fresh.
看起来 是新的
I'm sorry.
对不起
I had to.
当时我不得不
I'm sorry.
抱歉
- I hesitated. - Rose...
- 我犹豫了 - 萝丝
you're so brave and strong and bold.
你这么勇敢 坚强 倔强
Sadly,you'll have many other opportunities to kill Strigoi.
唉 你会有很多其他机会来杀死血族
You lied about your feelings for me.
关于对我的感觉 你撒了谎
Yes. I did.
是的 我承认
Why would you do that?
为什么那么做？
It's more than my age and my position at the academy.
这不只是我的年纪和在学院里职责的事情
Our allegiance is to the Moroi.
我们的效忠的是莫里族
If I let myself love,
如果我爱上一个人
I wouldn't throw myself in front of the princess.
我奋不顾身去保护的就不会是公主了
I would throw myself in front of you.
我挡在身后的 将是你
It's funny.
有意思
Your reasons for not loving me just...
你不敢爱我的理由
make me love you more.
让我更加爱你了
I want you to kiss me without a magic charm forcing you to do it.
我想要你发自内心地吻我 不像上次那样
That's not a great idea.
这样真的好么
Please.
求你了
Everyone's at the banquet. Just...
大家都在宴会上呢 只是
one last kiss.
就这最后一个吻
Yes! Yes,yes!
好 好 好
Yes! Are you not entertained?!
好 我真是太厉害了
My name is Rose Hathaway,
我是萝丝·海瑟薇
and I'm not your normal teenage girl,
我不是普普通通的青春期女生
but I guess,is there really such a thing?
实际上我在想 真的有哪个青春期女生是平淡无奇的么？
Every life has rules,traditions,friends and enemies,
每个生命都有自己的规矩 原则 朋友和敌人
sheer terror and incredible joy,
纯粹的恐惧和完全的欢乐
but I've learned...
但我学到了
Whoa! Watch where you're going there,bird.
哎哟 看好路啊 小鸟
Are you kidding me?
不会吧？
It's you,isn't it?
难道 就是你？
Come...
来吧
my shadow-kissed soul mate.
影吻的灵魂伴侣
Well,same to you,buddy!
好吧 那我也不鸟你 老兄
Now!
现在
Soon.
指日可待